「翻譯」日豐味兒牛奶器
「校對」somehacker
「時間軸」大鯀治水  芒果樹葉  chance-coco
「後期」bongpong
「總監」somehacker
該死
Shit!
狗娘養的司機
Crazy-drivin'motherfucker.
-該死  -過來
- Shit. - Come on. Come on.
馬文  你來幹什麼
Hey! Hey, Marvin, what are you doin'?
他是我的  傑克  滾邊兒去
He's mine, Jack. Get lost.
去你媽的  這是我的犯人
Fuck you, he's yours! He's mine.
艾迪分配給我的  你他媽想幹什麼
Eddie assigned this guy to me. What the hell are you doin'?
那你找艾迪理論去  錢我收了
Well then go straighten it out with Eddie. I'll collect the money.
追他的時候我差點被殺  他對我開槍呢
I almost got killed tryin' to get this guy. He shot at me!
退後  媽的  他是我的  明白嗎
Back off, goddamn it! I said I'm takin' him, all right?
-好的  馬文  -這傢伙值一千二呢
- All right. All right. Marvin. - This guy's worth 1,200!
好的  馬文  咱倆這交情爭什麼呀
Okay, okay, Marvin. What the hell we fightin' for? We're friends...
不是針對你  傑克  不過請你滾開行嗎
Hey, nothin' personal, Jack, but fuck off, all right?
淡定點  天哪  馬文  小心
Take it easy. Jesus! Marvin, watch out!
這他媽怎麼回事  你們不是警察嗎
What the fuck goin' on? You guys ain't cops.
不  我們是跳芭蕾的
No, we're ballet dancers.
你媽沒教過你禮貌待人嗎
Your mother ever teach you how to react to strangers?
比如不要向他們開槍
Not shoot at 'em. Huh?
馬文  車我開走了
Hey, Marvin. Thanks for the car.
你先睡會  一會我把車開回來
You sleep, and I'll bring it back a little later.
午夜狂奔
抓了個人  古奇
Got a delivery for you, Gooch.
好啊  傑克  蘇打水機壞了這麼久你都不修
Good, Jack. The soda machine's been out for a week and a half.
幫我簽個收  這次抓到誰
Check that for me, would ya? What do we got here?
好的  給你添麻煩了嗎
All right. Give you any trouble?
你給我添麻煩了嗎
Did you give me any trouble?
-操你媽的  -一點不麻煩
- Fuck you, man! - He didn't give me any trouble.
-走吧  過來  -你們這幫王八蛋
- Walk! Move! - Fuck you too, man!
-我他媽可清楚自己有什麼權利  -過來
- I know my motherfuckin' rights! - Move it!
手貼牆
Slap it.
保釋金債券代理 24小時營業
莫斯康保釋代理
Mascone's Bail Bonds.
不  僅限現金  支票和刷卡都不行
No, it's cash only. No checks, no cards.
抱歉  女士  我們有規定
I'm sorry, ma'am. That's the policy.
真遺憾沒能幫到您  抱歉
I wish I could help you out. Sorry.
剛把布爾歇送進去  艾迪在嗎
Just dropped off Bouchet. Is Eddie in?
你終於抓到人了  傑克
So you finally caught someone, Jack.
-傑裏  他在嗎  -真了不起
- Jerry, is he in? - I think that's terrific.
傑克  我昨晚就開始找你了  抓到誰了
Jack, been tryin' to reach you since last night. What do you got for me?
-你找我  -是啊
- You were tryin' to reach me? - Yeah.
-布爾歇  -他啊
- It's Bouchet. - Ooh, Bouchet.
好樣的  傑克  九百塊對吧
Good score, Jack. Nine hundred, right?
-不  是一千二  -不  九百
- No, it's 1,200. - No, nine.
是  是一千二  別這樣
That's... That's 1,200. Come on.
對  對  你說的沒錯
No. Yeah. Yeah, you're right.
我胃疼的要命
My stomach's killin' me.
我得去秦盧餐廳吃個早飯
I'm goin' over to Chin Loo's for breakfast.
-順便和你談談  -談什麼
- I wanna talk to you. - About what?
-到那兒再說  -能先把錢給我嗎
- I'll talk to you over there. - Could I have my money first?
當然  難不成你覺得我會賴賬
Of course. What do you think? I'm gonna try to stiff you?
你  不可能  他從來沒賴過賬
You? Never! He would never try and stiff me.
-這話怎麼像在諷刺我  -那不能
- Do I detect some kind of sarcasm here? - Never.
你以為我家喻戶曉的信譽是怎麼來的
Where do I, I, I... Where have I inherited this reputation?
傑裏可以作證  我在和別人做生意時
I have never done business with anybody, and Jerry is my witness,
從來  從來沒有
that I have ever, ever, ever...
我的保釋所有沒有
Does that phone ever ring...
有沒有接到過一次投訴電話
Has that phone ever rang with a complaint about me?
從來沒有  一次也沒有  走吧  早餐我請
Never. Never. So let's go. I'll buy you some breakfast.
-我從不吃早飯  -那就當提前吃午飯了  走吧
- I don't eat breakfast. - Then have an early lunch. Let's go.
聽說過喬納森·馬度卡斯這個人嗎
You ever hear of a guy named Jonathan Mardukas?
-"公爵"  我知道  -說來聽聽
- The Duke. Yeah, I know who he is. - What do you know?
他在某個賭棍手下當會計師
He's that accountant that embezzled a couple of million
偷了人幾百萬然後全捐給了慈善機構
from some Vegas wise guy and gave it to charity.
沒錯  不過不是幾百萬
That's very good. Only thing is that it wasn't a couple of million.
是一千五百萬
It was $15 million.
而且不是什麼賭棍  是吉米·塞拉諾
It wasn't some Vegas wise guy. It was Jimmy Serrano.
知道  我能看懂報紙
I know. I know. I can read the papers.
無意揭你傷疤
Well, look, I don't wanna bring up the past,
不過塞拉諾不就是當初使手段
but isn't Serrano the guy that ran you out of Chicago
把你從芝加哥逼走的人嗎
when he was runnin' things back there?
-和他沒關係  -是哦
- He didn't run me out. - Yeah, right, right, right.
那你為什麼辭了警察來幹這狗屎行當
You gave up bein' a cop to do this shit?
-好吧  說重點  -重點就是  傑克
- All right, what's the point? - The point, Jack.
我把那個會計師保出來了
I bailed out the accountant.
那時候我還不知道他給誰幹活
See, I didn't know who he was at the time.
不然說什麼也不會給他代理
Had I known, there was no way I would've put up the bond.
塞拉諾肯定早晚
I mean, it's only a matter of time
得讓他從地球上消失
before Serrano vanishes this guy from the planet,
我就得賠四十五萬
and I'm out 450,000.
你保他花了四十五萬嗎
You're out 450,000 on this guy?
-不  不是  -不是嗎
- No. No. - No.
因為有你在  你是這行的翹楚
Because I got you, and you're the best,
一定能把他抓回來
and you're gonna find him and bring him back.
好吧
Yeah, right.
你怎麼知道這傢伙還活著
How do you even know this guy is still alive?
因為他腦子進水了
Because this guy is crazy.
寄了一堆明信片給塞拉諾
He sends postcards to Serrano,
告訴他  花他的錢玩的很開心
he's tellin' him what a great time he's havin' with his money.
離期限還有多久
How much time you got left?
週五午夜  不然我就得賠四十五萬
Friday midnight I default. I eat the 450.
這週五  只有五天  你逗我呢
This Friday? That's five days. Forget it.
-自己去找他吧  把錢給我  -好吧  聽我說
- You go find him. Give me my money. - All right. Listen to me.
這次我付你四...我付你五萬
I'll give you four... I'll give you fifty grand.
五萬  找你要一千二都那麼難  算了吧
Fifty grand? I gotta chase you down for 1,200. Forget about it.
不  不  傑克  拜託了
No, no, Jack, please.
拜託個屁  說什麼我都不接  還有什麼活
"Jack"? "Jack" nothin'. Forget it. What else you got?
天哪  沒別的活了  只有這個了
God! I ain't got nothin'. This is it.
你要找不到這傢伙  我就破產了
If you don't find this guy, I'm outta business.
艾迪  十萬我才做
Eddie... I'll do it for a hundred thousand.
十萬  你瘋了嗎
A hundred thousand? Are you outta your mind?
這活兒多容易  簡直輕而易舉  老天爺
This is an easy gig. It's a midnight run, for Christ's sakes!
你還不知道吧  我已經厭倦挨槍子了
Maybe you haven't noticed, but I'm tired of gettin' shot at.
我不想再幹這種操蛋的工作
I'm tired of this miserable fuckin' business,
和各種人渣打交道
every lowlife that I run into.
要付就得付合理的報酬
If you're gonna pay me, you gotta pay me what's right.
要我幹這活  就給我應得的報酬
You want me for this job? Give me what's right.
首先  這傢伙是個會計  他不會對你開槍的
First of all, the guy is an accountant. He's not gonna shoot you.
你只要找到他
All you have to do is find him,
塞袋子裏還是打昏他都隨你  帶回來就行
you put him in a bag, hit him with a rubber hose, bring him home.
說起來容易  告訴你
Oh, that's easy for you to say. Listen to me.
十萬  少一個子都不行  而且要立合同
It's a hundred thousand, no more, no less, and I want a contract.
-還要合同  -沒錯  白紙黑字
- "Contract"? Contract? - That's right. I want it in writing.
十萬美元
One hundred thousand dollars,
週五晚前給你把"公爵"抓回來
and I'll have the Duke here for you by Friday night.
現在能先把那一千二給我嗎
Now, can I have my 1,200, please?
你比我保的任何一個罪犯都黑
You're worse than any crook I ever put a bond up for.
斯坦利  斯坦
Stanley? Stan.
-老夥計  近來可好  來這幹什麼  -別來無恙
- Hey, Big Dog. How are you? What are you doin' here? - How ya doin'?
得請你幫個忙
Listen. I need a favor.
我得查一下喬納森·馬度卡斯的登記資料
I need to see the booking slip of a Jonathan Mardukas.
馬度卡斯
M-A-R-D-U-K-A-S.
在這呢
Here you go.
代號 R-親屬
-就是它  -什麼
- Yes, sir. - What's that?
他被捕後打的第一通電話
The number he called right after he was arrested.
區號212  我得去紐約了
你是傑克·沃爾什嗎
Are you Jack Walsh?
-讓一下  -你是不是傑克·沃爾什
- Excuse me. - Are you Jack Walsh?
抱歉  我認識你嗎
I'm sorry. Do I know you?
阿朗佐·莫斯利  聯調局
Alonzo Mosely, F.B.I.
徽章不錯  在哪兒買的
Oh, that's a nice badge. How can I get one of those?
-我想和你談談  傑克  -是嗎  和我秘書預約吧
- I wanna talk to you. Jack. - Yeah? I want you to call my social secretary.
好笑嗎  我想和你談談
Yeah, very funny. I wanna talk to you.
放手  把手放開
Take your ha... Take your hands off me!
老天  別激動
Geez! Take it easy!
-在洛杉磯橫穿馬路罰款十塊知道嗎  -閉嘴
- You know it's a $10 fine for jaywalking in Los Angeles? - Shut up!
我想知道你是不是在辦
What I wanna know is, are you working on anything
喬納森·馬度卡斯的案子
having to do with Jonathan Mardukas?
沒聽說過這人
Never heard of him.
你一定聽說過
Well, I believe you have heard of him.
我告訴你  混球
Let me tell you something, asshole.
吉米·塞拉諾我們查了六年了
We've been working on this Jimmy Serrano thing for about six years.
馬度卡斯現在是關鍵
Mardukas is my shot.
我要把他送上聯邦法庭
I'm gonna bring him in to federal court,
而不是讓你這種當警察時抓捕不利
and I don't want any third-rate rent-a-thug
只好轉行去當三流賞金獵人的貨插手
who couldn't cut it as a cop in Chicago
把他抓回洛杉磯  以保內出逃起訴他
bringing him to L.A. on some bullshit local charge.
聽明白了嗎
Do I make myself understood?
能問你件事嗎
Can I ask you something?
你們的墨鏡真不錯
These sunglasses, they're really nice.
是政府專門配發的
Are they government-issued,
還是你們在同一家店買的
or do you guys go to the same store to get 'em?
聽明白我的話了嗎
Do I make myself understood?
你沒有幽默感嗎
Can't you take a joke?
讓他滾
Get him outta here.
-別啊  再多聊會啊  -滾吧
- No, let's talk some more. - Get the fuck outta here.
我要有什麼消息一定告訴你  祝你愉快
If I hear anything, I'll let you know. Have a nice day.
謝謝
Thank you.
我能把我的太陽鏡要回來嗎
Think I can have my sunglasses back?
你的太陽鏡  接好了
Here's your sunglasses. Go.
謝了  也謝謝這個
Thanks. Thanks for this too.
"阿朗佐·莫斯利"
"Alonzo Mosely."
阿朗佐
Alonzo.
-怎麼樣  -我覺得  不錯
- How's that? - Looks fine... to me.
我找哈羅德·朗文  謝謝
Harold Longman, please.
哈里  我是傑克·沃爾什  別來無恙
Harry? Jack Walsh. How ya doin'?
那個電話的地址你查到了嗎
You got that address check on that phone number for me?
好的  十分感謝  代我向朱莉問好  再見
Okay. Thanks a lot, Harry. Say hello to Julie for me. Okay, bye.
謝謝
Thank you.
你是傑克·沃爾什吧
You Jack Walsh?
-誰派你來的  -應該是了
- Who wants to know? - Answer "Yes."
我們有話給你說
We'd really like to have a word with you.
-是嗎  關於什麼的  -很多錢  中彩票一樣
- Oh, yeah? What about? - It involves big cash, lotto prizes.
我就長話短說了
I'll make it short and sweet.
我的老大對你的到來很感興趣
People I work for, really interested in your visit here.
是嗎  你為誰工作
Oh, yeah? Who are the people you work for?
你在芝加哥時的老朋友
An old friend of yours from the Chicago days.
你是來抓"公爵"的吧  你覺得他在紐約
You're here for the Duke. You think he's in New York,
英雄所見略同
and we think you're right.
夾克不錯  羊皮的嗎
That's a nice jacket. What is it, uh, goatskin?
拜託  喬伊  看看場合  別管他
Come on, Joey. Please, will ya? Never mind him.
我聽說幾年前你不肯跟我老大合作
The way I hear it... you didn't cooperate with my boss a few years back.
你確定你沒聽錯
Is that the way you heard it?
對  不過告訴你個好消息  傑克
Yeah. But I got a news flash for you, Jack.
他肯出比洛杉磯保釋代理那幫蠢貨
He'd pay more for the Duke than
更高的價雇你去找"公爵"
that putz bail bondsman back in L.A.
-是嗎  高多少  -一百萬怎麼樣
- Oh, yeah? How much more? - How about a one with six zeroes?
-你有話要說嗎  -什麼
- Are you gonna propose? - "Propose"?
不然別老瞪著我  行嗎
Propose. 'Cause if you're not, quit starin' at me. Okay?
我瞪你  明明是你在瞪我
Starin' at you? You're staring at me.
拜託  喬伊  一邊兒去好嗎
Come on, Joey, back off. Will you, please? ??
沃爾什先生  您的班車在206號發車點
Mr. Walsh, your car's located in space number 206.
您可以乘坐擺渡車過去
You can catch our shuttle bus just through these doors.
-謝謝  -這是我的電話  傑克
- Thank you. - Here's my number, Jack.
說找托尼·達爾沃就行
Ask for Tony Darvo. That's me.
隨時隨地都可以打給我
They'll put you through to wherever I am.
這次可要把握機會  好嗎
And be good to yourself this time. Okay?
代我向吉米問好
Tell Jimmy I said hello.
-您好  -您好  是尼爾森夫人嗎
- Hello? - Hello? Mrs. Nelson?
-是  -我是聯調局特工阿朗佐·莫斯利
- Yes. - Alonzo Mosely, Federal Bureau of Investigation.
-下午好  -午安
- How are you this afternoon? - I'm fine.
我就直奔主題了  尼爾森夫人
Let me get to the point, if I may, Mrs. Nelson.
洛杉磯分處的探員
An agent in our Los Angeles office
發現了一處被忽略的細節
discovered a detail that was overlooked until now.
喬納森·馬度卡斯被捕後第一通電話
It seems that when a Jonathan Mardukas was arrested,
好像是打給您的
you were the first person he called.
對嗎  尼爾森夫人
Is that correct, Mrs. Nelson?
-您在聽嗎  尼爾森夫人  -在
- Are you there, Mrs. Nelson? - Yes.
很顯然  這是條重要的線索
Needless to say, this is a matter of great concern to us,
不麻煩的話
and if it would not be too much trouble,
希望您明早能到
we would like you to come down
聯邦廣場26號來一趟
tomorrow morning to 26 Federal Plaza.
-可以嗎  -應該沒問題
- Do you think you could do that? - I suppose so.
-早上九點行嗎  -好的
- About 9.00 A.M.? - Yes.
說找阿朗佐·莫斯利就行
Just ask for Agent Alonzo Mosely.
感謝您的合作  祝您愉快
Thanks for your cooperation. Have a nice day.
-你好  -達納  我是海倫
- Hello? - Dana? It's Helen.
聯調局的人剛來過電話
The F.B.I. just called.
要和我談談喬納森的事
They want to speak to me about Jonathan.
-天哪  海倫  -海倫  怎麼了
- Oh, my God. Helen. - Helen, what's going on?
喬納森  調查局的人找我了
Jonathan, the F.B.I. just called.
他們知道你被捕那晚我們通過電話
They know we spoke the night you were arrested.
趕緊把電話掛了  海倫
Hang up the phone, Helen. Right now.
真是美妙的旋律
Ah, sweet music.
行李箱裏還有地方放嗎
Do you think there's enough room in the suitcase?
有
Yeah.
檢查過這個了嗎  洗髮水什麼的  怎麼了
Did you check this one? Shampoo and all that... What?
-怎麼了  喬恩  -不知道
- What is it, Jon? - I don't know.
好了  好了  海蒂  好了
Okay. Okay, Heidi. Okay.
阿朗佐·莫斯利  聯邦調查局  你被捕了
Alonzo Mosely, F.B.I! You're under arrest!
把這該死的狗弄出去  把狗牽出去  女士
Get this fuckin' dog outta here! Get this dog outta here, ma'am!
你別走  在這待著
Not you. You stay there.
-女士  把狗弄出去  -去吧  去吧
- Get the dog, ma'am. - Do it. Do it. ??
海蒂  過來  乖狗狗  過來  過來
Heidi. Come on, girl. Come on. That's a good girl. Come on, come on.
別動  不然隔著玻璃給你一槍
Don't move, or I'll shoot you right through the glass.
過來  雙手貼牆
Get over here. Put your hands up against the wall.
雙手貼牆  腳分開
Your hands up against the wall. Spread your feet.
放鬆點  沒事的
Relax. There won't be a problem.
左手放到後腦勺那
Put your left hand behind your head.
左手放到  沒錯
Put your left... That's it.
肯尼迪機場
你要帶我去機場嗎
You're taking me to the airport, aren't you?
你看起來可不像調查局的人
You don't look like an F.B.I. agent to me.
是嗎  你也不像"公爵"啊
Yeah? Well, you don't look like a duke to me.
你要是調查局的特工
If you're an F.B.I. agent,
應該直接把我帶去你的辦公室
why don't you take me to the F.B.I. office?
你再不閉嘴
If you don't be quiet,
我保證讓你記一輩子
this is gonna be the worst trip of your life.
你為吉米·塞拉諾工作是嗎
You work for Jimmy Serrano, don't you?
我才不替那個王八蛋做事
I don't work for that piece of shit.
你的保釋代理人雇我
Your bail bondsman hired me to
把你帶回洛杉磯
bring you back to L.A., and that's what I'm doin'.
-我有錢  -我知道
- I got money, you know? - I'm sure you do.
-你要多少我都給你  -閉上你的嘴
- I'll give you whatever you want. - Start by shutting up.
這才兩分鐘  我已經開始煩你了
I know you all of two minutes, and already I don't like you.
真遺憾  我倒挺喜歡你的
Gee, that's too bad. I really like you.
飛機裏我不能銬你
I can't keep you cuffed on a commercial flight,
槍也得辦托運
and I gotta check my gun with my luggage,
但你要敢耍花樣  我就扭斷你的脖子
but you fuck with me once, and I'm gonna break your neck.
-我不能坐飛機  -什麼
- I can't fly. - What?
你沒聽錯  我不能坐飛機
You heard me, I can't fly.
不  不  這可輪不到你決定  夥計
No, no. You're gonna have to do better than that, pal.
我不需要決定什麼
I don't have to do better than that
因為事實如此
because it's the truth I can't fly.
我有恐飛癥
I suffer from aviophobia.
-什麼癥  -我就是不能坐飛機
- What does that mean? - It means I can't fly.
我還有恐高癥和幽閉恐懼癥
I also suffer from acrophobia and claustrophobia.
你要再不聽話
I'll tell you what. If you don't cooperate,
馬上就會得"拳頭恐懼癥"
you're gonna suffer from "Fistaphobia."
-莫斯康保釋代理  -傑裏  讓艾迪接電話
- Mascone's Bail Bonds. - Jerry, put Eddie on the phone.
-傑克  進展如何  -抓到他了
- Jack, what's the progress? - I got him.
-抓到誰了  -"公爵"  就站我旁邊呢
- You got who? - The Duke. He's standin' right here.
你已經抓到他了
You got him? Already?
當然  要打個招呼嗎
Sure do. Wanna say hello?
跟你的代理人艾迪·莫斯康問個好
Say hello to your bail bondsman, Eddie Mascone.
-你好  -聽見沒
- Hello. - There you go.
-活生生的喬納森·馬度卡斯  -傑克  愛死你了
- Jonathan Mardukas in the flesh. - Jack, I love ya!
我不是在做夢吧  你在哪兒找到他的
What happened? How did this happen? Where'd you find him?
紐約  我們現在在機場
I found him in New York. We're at the airport.
老天爺  太好了
Holy Christ! This is wonderful!
真是個好消息
This is wonderful news!
今晚午夜到你辦公室
I'll be in your office by midnight tonight,
聽清楚了  艾迪
and I'm tellin' you right now, Eddie.
這次別跟我扯那些淡  今晚我就要拿到錢
I don't wanna hear any bullshit. I want the money tonight.
快把錢從你的小金庫裏取出來
So go empty out one of your Swiss bank accounts.
傑克  你放一萬個心
No, Jack, don't you have to worry about nothin'.
這錢花的絕對值
This is the best money I ever spent.
-好  幾個小時後見  -好的  再見
- Okay. See you in a few hours. - All right. See ya later. Night.
-你興奮什麼呢  -傑裏  沃爾什抓到"公爵"了
- So what's that all about? - Jerry, Walsh got the Duke!
沃爾什抓到"公爵"了
Walsh got the Duke?
-抓到他了  抓到"公爵"了  -開玩笑吧
- He got him! He got the Duke! - No kiddin'?
一定要慶祝一下  我買甜甜圈去
This calls for a celebration. I'll get some doughnuts.
沃爾什怎麼這麼快就找到他了
How do you think Walsh found him so fast?
-你好  -托尼  我是傑裏
- Yeah, hello. - Uh, Tony, uh, this is Jerry.
-哪個傑裏  -傑裏·蓋斯勒  你幹什麼呢
- Jerry who? - Jerry Geisler. What are you doing?
吃晚飯呢  有事嗎
I'm eatin' dinner. What do you want?
抱歉打擾你  不過我探聽到
Look, I hate to bother you, but I thought you'd like to know
沃爾什在紐約找到"公爵"了
that Walsh found the Duke in New York.
他們坐飛機回來  大概午夜著陸
They're flyin' in tonight. They should arrive around midnight.
-有好處別忘了我  -好  好  好
- Don't forget me, babe. - Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah, kid, yeah.
謝了  晚安
Thanks. Good night.
看來你的老朋友找到那個會計了
Looks like your old friend found the accountant.
他們午夜在洛杉磯著陸
They'll be flying into L.A. around midnight.
在機場安排人手  明白嗎
Have 'em met at the airport. You understand?
明白
Done.
-需要我幫您保管外套嗎  -不了  謝謝
- Can I take your coat? - No, that's fine. Thanks.
-您的外套呢  -不用  不用
- May I take your coat? - No, no...
頭等艙就是好  要是每次都坐就好了
First class is nice. I can make a habit out of this.
-晚上好  先生們  -晚上好
- Good evening, gentlemen. - Good evening to you.
起飛前想喝點什麼嗎
Would either of you like a drink before we take off?
來兩杯你們最好的香檳
Yes, we would like one of your finest champagnes.
好的
Certainly.
看看這個
Let's see. Ah, look at this.
也就美國有了  多好的國家啊
Only in America. What a country. Huh?
難以置信  我得嘗嘗這牛排
Unbelievable. I think I'm gonna have the steak.
-你呢  -我不餓
- How about you? - I'm not hungry.
要不你就點份龍蝦吧
Well, why don't you, then, get the lobster.
這樣就湊成海陸大餐了
Because then I can get a little surf and turf action goin'.
我有恐懼癥
I got a problem.
我不能坐飛機  沒跟你開玩笑
I can't fly. I don't think you're takin' me seriously.
-我也沒開玩笑  -我不能待在飛機上
- I'm takin' you very seriously. - I can't be on this plane.
別以為我不知道你的事
You think I haven't heard your story before?
你當我是剛出道的菜鳥嗎
Who do you think you're traveling with, a fuckin' novice?
懂我意思了嗎  這就對了  乖乖的
You know what I'm talkin'about? That's it. Settle in.
想找飛機上別的乘客
If you wanna get up and talk social and mingle with
談天說地  都隨你
the rest of the passengers, be my guest.
諒你也逃不了
You ain't goin' nowhere.
我看這有幾個挺有錢的人
There's a couple of nice-lookin' people here.
上流社會  和你一樣的人
Better class of people. Your class.
沒準也盜用公款了
Probably all embezzlers too.
跟我一起飛  飛到遠方去
Come fly with me. Come fly away.
放輕鬆好嗎
Why don't you just try and relax?
我  我不能
I... Look, I ca...
鎮定點  放鬆  鎮定下來
Just calm down. Just relax and calm down.
-你興奮個什麼勁兒呢  -不是  不是...
- What are you gettin' so excited about? - It's not... It's...
不  我不行了  不行
No! I can't! I can't.
-不  不  我不行了  不行  -放鬆
- No! No! No! I can't. I can't. - Just relax.
放輕鬆  我怎麼跟你說的
Just relax. What did I tell ya?
-別跟我玩花招...-不  不  不  我告訴你
- Don't pull that shit on me... - No, no, no. No, no. I'm tellin' you.
我不行了  真不行
I can't do it. I can't do it.
-我真不行  不  我不行了  -給我過來
- I can't do it. No! I can't! - Get over there!
-這玩意會墜毀的  會掉下來的  -好了
- These things go down! These things go down! ?? - All right.
太大了  怎麼可能飛起來
It's too big! It can't go up!
好了  各位  請保持鎮定
All right, everyone. Just calm down.
-出什麼事了  -沒什麼  先生
- All right, what's the problem? - It's nothing, sir.
沒事  聯調局  阿朗佐·莫斯利
It's okay. Alonzo Mosely, F.B.I.
他由我負責
This man is in my custody.
我要帶他回洛杉磯  我保證他不會再鬧了
I'm takin' him to Los Angeles. There won't be any more problems.
我不想坐飛機  我真不能坐飛機
I don't wanna fly. I can't fly, really.
這個犯人不想坐飛機
You can't take a prisoner aboard an airplane
你就不該帶他登機  你應該知道
if he doesn't want to fly.  You should know that.
我知道  抱歉  我以為他在唬人
I do. I'm sorry. I thought he was bluffing. I thought he was bluffing.
我建議你們換種交通工具吧
I suggest you find some other mode of transportation.
到火車站
-你笑個屁  -我喜歡坐火車
- What the fuck are you smilin' about? - I love to travel by train.
是嗎  你當這是修學旅行嗎
Oh, yeah? What do you think this is, a class trip?
你怎麼火這麼大
Are you always this angry?
現在我心情好得不得了
Hey, look. Right now I'm in a great fuckin' mood.
但上車以後你要再挑事
You wait when I'm cooped up on that thing for a while,
我保證你再也笑不出來
You're not gonna be smilin'.
讓你哭著喊著求我送你進監獄
You're gonna be runnin' for that fuckin' jail cell.
還趕得上嗎
Still gonna make your schedule?
沒問題  剩14個小時呢
I'll make it, 14 hours to spare.
不錯  不錯  雙人間
Oh, nice, nice. It's a double.
-雙人間空間就比較大了  -你喜歡就好
- It's a double. There'll be a nice lot of room. - Glad you like it.
好  很不錯
Good. Very nice.
謝謝  謝
Thanks. Thank...
磨的我手腕疼  謝謝
'Cause they're starting to cut into my wrists. Thank you.
戴一會皮膚就受不了
You know, it just gets the skin after a while.
-進去  -你想幹什麼  怎麼了
- Get in there. - What do you want? What?
拜託  拜託
Oh, come on. Come on.
不  別這樣  為什麼把我關進來啊
No, you don't... Why would you do that?
旅途愉快  我住這間
You'll enjoy yourself. This is my room,
你住那間  晚安
and that's your room. Good night.
歡迎來到洛杉磯
有什麼可以效勞的嗎
Hey, can I, uh, help you guys?
我是調查局特工莫斯利
Special Agent Mosely, F.B.I.
莫斯利  你們怎麼都叫莫斯利
"Mosely"? Are all you guys named "Mosely"?
什麼意思
What are you talking about?
你是來接犯人的對嗎
You're here to pick up a prisoner, right?
-你怎麼知道  -他有恐飛癥
- How did you know that? - He was afraid to fly,
下飛機了
so he got off the plane.
和另一個莫斯利特工一起
He left with an Agent Mosely.
長官  這說明沃爾什拿了你的證件
Sir, that must mean that Walsh has your identification.
說
Yeah?
是蠢蛋一號嗎  讓蠢蛋二號接電話
Is this moron number one? Put moron number two on the phone.
好的  吉米  稍等
Yeah, Jimmy. He's, uh, right here. Hold on.
他挺生氣
He's pissed.
-怎麼了  -你不是說他坐飛機來嗎
- Yeah? - I thought you told me this guy was gonna be on the plane.
我們打探到的消息是這樣的
That's the information we got.??
"我們打探到的消息是這樣的"  告訴你
"That's the information we got." I wanna tell you something.
我要這個人從世上消失  越快越好
I want this guy taken out, and I want him taken out fast.
你和另一個蠢貨
You and that other dummy better
最好立馬親自動手結果了他
start getting more personally involved in your work,
否則我一鉛筆戳死你倆
or I'm gonna stab you through the heart with a fucking pencil.
-明白嗎  -明白  吉米
- Do you understand me? - You got it, Jimmy.
托尼  他沒生我的氣吧
Tony, he ain't mad at me, is he?
傑克
Jack?
傑克  這不合法吧
Jack, I th... I think this is illegal.
傑克  你不能把人這麼關在廁所裏
Jack, I don't think you can keep a person in a bathroom like this.
你  這地方太封閉了
Uh,you... It's very claustrophobic in here...
是嗎  這樣吧
Yeah, it is? Well, I'll tell you what.
等到了洛杉磯
When we get to L.A.,
記得把這事告訴監獄的心理醫生
you can tell the prison psychiatrist all about it.
我要窒息了  這裏面根本不通風
There's no air. There's no ventilation in here.
我跟你說過我有幽閉恐懼癥  拜託
I told you I was claustrophobic. Come on.
放我出來我又能怎樣
What do you think I'm gonna do?
從時速90英里的火車上跳下去嗎
Jump off a train moving 90 miles an hour?
傑克  傑克
Jack? Jack.
傑克
Jack?
太好了  謝謝  謝謝
Good. Thanks. Thanks.
多謝你了  太好了
Thanks a lot. Oh, good.
-坐下  -好的  太好了  你真好
- Sit down. - Oh, yeah, that's great. Very kind of you.
不錯  好多了  謝謝  真好
Nice. Much better. Thank you. Good.
你在幹什麼
What are you doing?
我嗎  算賬呢
What am I doin'? Arithmetic.
算賬  沒準我能幫上你  我搞會計的
Arithmetic? Maybe I can help you. I am an accountant.
我是這麼打算的
Well, you know, what I was thinkin',
等把你交出去  拿到錢以後
after I turn your ass in and collect my money,
開一家不錯的小咖啡館
I'm gonna open up a nice little coffee shop.
我到底值多少錢  能問問嗎
How much exactly are you getting for me, if I may ask?
這不是你該操心的事
I don't think that's any of your concern,
不過告訴你也就告訴你了
but I'll tell you just to... just to tell you.
-十萬  -十萬
- A hundred thousand. - A hundred thousand?
那我給你十萬是不是就能放我走了
Does that mean you'd take a hundred thousand to let me go?
-門都沒有  -二十萬
- Not by a long shot. - Two hundred thousand?
我這輩子就沒受過賄
I never took a payoff in my life,
更別說從你這樣的人身上破例了
and I'm not gonna start with someone like you.
-為什麼  -因為你是個該死的罪犯
- Why not? - Because you're a fuckin' criminal,
坐牢是你罪有應得
and you deserve to go where you're goin',
而我就是把你抓進去的人
and I'm gonna take you there.
再讓我聽到類似的話  我就揍爛你的臉
And if I hear more shit out of you, I'm gonna bust your head,
把你扔回該死的廁所
put you back in that fuckin' hole,
再把你的頭
and I'm gonna stick your head
狠狠地塞進馬桶裏
in the fuckin' toilet bowl and I'm gonna make it stay there.
還是提醒你一下  餐飲業可不好幹
Well, I have to tell you, a restaurant is a very tricky investment.
超過五成的人在半年內破產
More than half of them go under within the first six months.
我要是你的會計師  絕對大力反對你的想法
If I were your accountant, I'd strongly advise you against it.
是嗎  可惜你不是我的會計師
You would? Well, you're not my accountant.
我只是假設我是你的會計師  就...
No, I mean, if I were your accountant, I'd...
我把你從這帶走...
I told you, I took you out of here...
不  我就是說非常不好幹
No, I'm just saying that it's a very very tricky business,
如果我是你的會計師
and if I were your accountant,
我一定會大力反對你投資餐飲
I would really strongly have to advise you against it,
作為  作為你的會計師
as a... as an accountant.
-你不是我的會計師  -我知道
- You're not my accountant. - I realize I'm not your accountant.
我說假如我是你的會計師而已
I'm just saying if I were your accountant.
傑裏  他他媽怎麼就錯過飛機了
Jerry, how the hell could he miss the goddamn plane?
他從機場打的電話啊
He called from the airport!
好吧  打給馬文吧  對嗎
All right. It's time to bring in Marvin. All right?
打給他  他在匹茲堡呢
Call him up. He's in Pittsburgh.
-馬文·道夫勒  -對  道夫勒
- Marvin Dorfler? - Yeah, Dorfler.
D開頭  名字叫王八蛋那個
Under "D" in the rolodex for "Jerk", Jerry.
至少分我點薯條吧
Can I at least have some french fries?
不可能  混球  閉嘴吧
I said no, pecker breath. Now shut up.
我是道夫勒
Yeah, Dorfler.
馬文  老夥計  還好有你在
Marvin? Sweetheart, am I glad I got you.
-老哥  有個活給你  -說吧  聽著呢
- Boy, do I have a job for you! - Yeah? I'm listening.
首先  我得向你道歉
First of all, I gotta apologize,
我們之前到處找你
because we were trying to find you,
這活實在太重要了  但我找不到你
and it's a very important job, and I couldn't find you.
只好給了沃爾什  他卻搞砸了  所以
So I had to give it to Walsh, but he's fucking it up, so...
真不明白你為什麼還要雇那個傻逼
I don't know why you keep hiring that fuckin' guy.
我知道  對不起
I know. I... I apologize.
你是這行的翹楚
You are the best at what you do. You know that?
-聽說過喬納森·馬度卡斯嗎  -沒
- Now listen. Do you know who Jonathan Mardukas is? - No.
喬納森·馬度卡斯  "公爵"
Jonathan Mardukas? The Duke?
艾迪  我從沒聽說過這人
Eddie, I never heard of him.
好吧  不重要  重要的是
All right, listen, that's not important. What's important is that
你得找到他並把他帶回來  好嗎
you find him and you bring him back, okay?
我最後和他們通話時他倆在紐約
Now, last I heard, he had him in New York,
現在我也不知道他倆跑哪兒去了
and now I don't know where the hell they are.
找到他們  沃爾什的工錢就歸你了
If you find 'em, I'll give you what I'm givin' Walsh.
是嗎  多少
Yeah? What's that?
兩萬五
Twenty-five thousand.
但你得在週五午夜前帶他回來
But you gotta have him back by Friday midnight,
不然一切免談
otherwise the deal is off.
別擔心  艾迪  為了那兩萬五
Yeah, well, don't worry, Eddie. For 25 grand,
抬也給抬回來了
I'll bring him in on a silver platter.
隨你怎麼辦  把人帶來就行了
Bring him, uh, any way you want, but bring him, okay?
再見
Bye.
-喂  人渣  -我叫卡爾米  混蛋
- Hey, scumbag. - My name's Carmine, fucko.
好吧  卡爾米  今天算你走運
Yeah, well, Carmine, today's your lucky day.
-走什麼運  -閉嘴
- Why is today my lucky day? - Shut up!
對  對  我名叫傑克·沃爾什
Yeah. Yeah, my name is, uh, Jack Walsh.
抱歉  全名是約翰·衛斯理·沃爾什
Uh, excuse me. John Wesley Walsh.
我信用卡丟了
Yeah, I think I lost my credit card.
能幫我查查最後在哪兒用過嗎
Can you tell me the last place I used it?
號碼是7314-8395-2113
Yeah, 7314-8395-2113.
中央火車站的美鐵辦公室嗎
The Amtrak office, Grand Central Station?
對  對  我想起來了
Huh. Oh, yeah, yeah. I remember that now.
好的  十分感謝
Yeah, okay. Yeah, thanks very much.
順便把這張卡作廢吧
Hey, uh, maybe we oughta cancel that card, huh?
好的  謝謝
Yeah. Thank you.
知道動脈硬化嗎
Familiar with the word "Arteriosclerosis"?
膽固醇呢
Cholesterol?
我可以給你列一張均衡飲食的清單
If you want, I'll outline a complete balanced diet for you.
記得從監獄寄給我
Well, mail it to me from "C" Block.
-為什麼要吃這個  -為什麼  好吃唄
- Why would you eat that? - Why? 'Cause it tastes good.
-但對身體不好  -我知道
- But it's not good for you. - I'm aware of that.
明知對身體不好為什麼還要吃呢
Why do something that you know is not good for you?
因為我不在乎
Because I don't think about it.
你這是在逃避現實
Well, that's living in denial.
-逃避現實  -對
- Living in denial? - Yeah.
-這我也知道  -你什麼都知道
- I'm aware of that. - So you're aware of all your behavior,
卻依然堅持做對自己無益的事
yet you continue to do things that aren't good for you.
聽起來有些蠢  你說呢  傑克
That sounds sort of foolish. Don't you think so, Jack?
不  偷了吉米·塞拉諾一千五百萬才叫蠢
No. Stealing $15 million from Jimmy Serrano sounds foolish.
-我以為自己不會被捕  -這才叫逃避現實
- I didn't think I'd get caught. - Now, that's livin' in denial.
-我知道  -所以你什麼都知道
- I'm aware of that. - Oh, so you're aware of your behavior,
也依然堅持做對自己無益的事
and yet you continue to do things that aren't good for you.
我看也挺蠢的
Sounds kind of foolish to me.
-你說呢  喬恩  -是很蠢
- Don't you think, Jon? - It was foolish.
但是從黑幫手中偷了一千五百萬
But taking 15 million in Mob money
捐給慈善機構能幫助很多人
and giving it to charity was good for a lot of people.
你惹毛一個黑手黨老大
So you pissed off a mafioso killer
就為了讓一堆陌生人對你感恩戴德
just to be loved by a bunch of fuckin' strangers.
-真是好主意  -你不希望自己受人愛戴嗎
- That makes a lot of sense. - Don't you want to be loved?
-很多人都愛我  -是嗎
- Lots of people love me. - Really?
誰
Who?
我前妻和女兒在芝加哥
I got an ex-wife and I got a daughter in Chicago.
他們怎麼受得了你這張嘴
How do they put up with all your sarcasm?
問得好  我們有九年沒見過面了
Beautifully. I haven't seen either of them in nine years.
要不去看看他們
Think maybe we should go see them?
我看還是算了吧
No, I don't think maybe we should go see them.
不過多謝你的好意了
Thanks for the interest, though.
你幹這行他們肯定不好過吧
The job must have been tough on 'em.
-我以前不幹這個  -那你做什麼的
- I didn't do this then. - What did you do?
-警察  -你在芝加哥當警察
- I was a cop. - You were a cop in Chicago?
那你一定對吉米·塞拉諾瞭如指掌
Then you must know all about Jimmy Serrano.
-你哪來的權利問這問那  -不行嗎
- Do you have the right to ask me certain questions? - I think I do.
-不  不行  -我覺得我有權問你
- No, you don't. - I think I do.
-不  你沒有  -為什麼
- No, you don't. - Why not?
吃完了  走吧
Dinner's over. Let's go.
我就知道這趟夠我受的  夥計
I can see this is gonna be some fuckin' trip, boy.
換我就不會擔心  傑克
I wouldn't worry about it, Jack.
咱倆在一起待不了多久了
I'm not gonna be with you that much longer.
-什麼意思  -以我對塞拉諾的瞭解
- What do you mean? - Well, with what I know about Serrano,
我一入獄  一天之內必死
if I go to jail, I'll be dead within 24 hours.
所以還不如趁早從你手裏開溜
So sooner or later, I'm gonna have to give you the slip.
那是
Sure.
難得把你逗笑一次
Glad you find it humorous.
走吧
- Let's go.
小費你只給兩美元
Two dollars? That's all you're gonna leave?
-那是15%  -那是13%
- That's 15%. - That's 13%.
這些人靠小費為生
These people depend on tips for a living.
有事嗎  先生
Uh, can I, uh, help you, sir?
我  我在找一個朋友  叫傑克·沃爾什
Yeah. Yeah, I... I'm lookin' for this buddy of mine. Jack Walsh.
他告訴我在車裏見
He told me he'd meet me on this train.
這呢  沃爾什  在D號臥鋪  下節車廂
Ah, yeah, Mr. Walsh. He's in Bedroom "D," Next car.
-那節車廂  -是的  先生  那邊走
- Uh, that next car? - Yes, sir, that way.
-謝謝  -不客氣  晚安
- Thanks. - Sure thing. Have a good night.
敢出聲就弄死你  混球
One word and you're dead, asshole.
他媽的  王八...
Holy shit! Son of a...
你他媽怎麼找到我在哪兒的
How the fuck did you find out where I am?
去你媽的  才不告訴你
Fuck you shit! I ain't tellin' you shit!
你這是在逼我用非常手段
You're gonna force me to do something I don't wanna do!
發生什麼事了
What's goin' on in here?
沒事  一切盡在掌控中
All right. Everything's under control.
別緊張  聯調局特工阿朗佐·莫斯利
Take it easy. Alonzo Mosely, F.B.I.
用電台聯繫下一站的當地警局
Radio ahead. I want the local police at the next stop
來逮捕這個人
to place this man under arrest.
-你他媽在說什麼呢  -你話太多了
- What the fuck are you talkin' about? - That's enough out of you!
快去  打電話報警
Go ahead. Get on the horn and call the cops.
好消息還是壞消息
Is this good news or bad news?
據說馬度卡斯和沃爾什改乘火車
Apparently, Mardukas and Walsh are on the Amtrak
前往洛杉磯了
headed to Los Angeles.
另一個賞金獵人想搶馬度卡斯
Another bounty hunter was arrested
失敗被捕了
after he tried to take Mardukas away.
20分鐘內把飛機備好
I want the jet ready in 20 minutes.
-傑克·沃爾什在哪兒  -他和另一個人
- Where's Jack Walsh? - Uh, he got off with the other guy
兩三站前就下車了
two or three stops ago.
-其實他叫莫斯利  -我才是莫斯利
- His real name's Mosely. - I'm Mosely!
請幫我接對方付費的電話  打給艾迪·莫斯康
I wanna make a collect call to a Eddie Mascone from a Jack Walsh.
莫斯康保釋代理
Mascone. Bail bonds.
傑裏  我是傑克  讓艾迪接電話
Jerry, it's Jack. Put Eddie on.
-天哪  傑克  你跑哪去了  -傑克  我來說
- Jesus, Jack! Where the hell you been? - Jack... I wanna talk to him.
-傑克  你在哪兒  -我在哪兒
- Jack, where are you? - Where am I?
艾迪  我倒要問問你
Eddie, I wanna ask you somethin'.
道夫勒怎麼也摻合進來了
How come Dorfler wound up on my ass?
你叫來的嗎  你個王八蛋
Did you put him on this, you son of a bitch?
等等  道夫勒  怎麼可能
Wait a minute. Dorfler? I don't even...
我怎麼可能派他去
How could I put Dorfler on you?
我連你在哪兒都不知道
I don't even know where the fuck you are.
你敢說和你一點關係也沒有
You had nothin' to do with it?
你在哪兒  "公爵"還在你手裏嗎
Where are you? You got the Duke or what?
-說的沒錯  -你在哪兒
- You're damn right I got him. - Well, where are you?
我在哪兒  我在...
Where am I? I'm somewhere between...
我也不清楚  托萊多和克利夫蘭之間吧
I don't know... Toledo and Cleveland.
-我們改乘巴士了  -搞定
- We're gettin' on a bus. - Bingo.
巴士  傑克  別...你瘋了嗎
Bus? Jack, don't get on a... What, are you outta your mind?
你能閉上嘴聽我說兩句嗎
Will you just shut up for a minute and listen to me?
我們改乘巴士
We're gettin' on a bus.
就告訴你一聲我們在路上了  拜
I wanted to let you know we're on our way, Okay? Bye.
別掛
Don't hang up!
該死  這傢伙到底在幹什麼
Shit! What the hell is this guy doin'?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我還是再去買點甜甜圈吧
Listen, uh, maybe I oughta get some doughnuts or somethin', huh?
兩張去洛杉磯的單程票  謝謝
Two one-way tickets to Los Angeles, please.
還趕得上嗎
Still gonna make our schedule?
別擔心  我會按時把你送到的
Don't worry. I'll get you there on time.
就甭心存幻想了
Don't have any illusions.
-幻想  -對  幻想
- "Illusions"? - Illusions. Illusions.
抱歉  先生  這張卡已經作廢了
I'm sorry, sir. This card's been canceled.
作廢了
Huh? It's been canceled?
不好意思  弄錯了吧  能再試一次嗎
I'm sorry. That's a mistake. Would you please try it again?
-已經試了兩次了  先生  -麻煩你再刷一次
- I checked it twice, sir. - Please try it again.
-請你再刷一次  -你按時還款了嗎
- Please try it again. - Did you pay the bill?
-閉嘴  -抱歉  先生  這張卡已經作廢了
- Shut up. - I'm sorry, sir. It's been canceled.
女士  不可能的  我按時還款的啊
Ma'am, that is impossible. I pay my bills.
這卡不可能已經作廢了
There is no way that that could be canceled.
-人家說作廢了  -閉嘴
- It's canceled. - Shut up!
-拜託  -卡已經作廢了  先生
- Please. - It's canceled, sir.
-女士  拜託  -您想換一張卡試試嗎
- Ma'am, please... - Would you like to try another credit card?
-現金也行  -我沒別的卡了  拜託
- Or cash. - I don't have other credit cards. Please.
-請你再試一次好嗎  -不
- Would you just try that again? - No.
好吧
All right.
阿朗佐...傑克·沃爾什  調查局特工
Alonzo... Uh, Jack Walsh, Federal Bureau of Investigation.
執行公務
This is official business.
我要帶他...他是我拘捕的犯人
I'm taking this man... I mean, he's in my custody.
我要帶他去洛杉磯  懂嗎  請你再刷一次
I'm taking him to Los Angeles, okay? So please try this once more.
證件上的名字可不是傑克·沃爾什  先生
Jack Walsh is not the name on that badge, sir.
需要我打給聯調局嗎
Would you like me to call the F.B.I.?
或者您還是付現金吧
Or would you like to pay cash?
多少錢
How much is it?
兩張票共兩百六十四美元
Two hundred and sixty-four dollars for two tickets.
兩百六十四  這是一百
Two sixty-four. Here's a hundred.
-帶錢了嗎  -不少呢
- Got any money on ya? - A lot.
這也叫不少錢
You call that a lot of money, huh?
買車票倒是夠了
Well, it's enough to get you where I'm gonna get you.
一  二  三  四  五  六  七
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
整個警局都出動了嗎
Got the whole fuckin' force after me, huh?
-你他媽又是誰  -聯調局特工莫斯利
- Who the fuck are you? - Special Agent Mosely, F.B.I.
他媽的  我什麼都沒干
Oh, goddamn it! I didn't do anything.
放鬆  就問你幾個問題而已
Relax. Just wanna ask you a few questions. That's all.
真客氣  隨便抽啊
Yeah. Fuckin' "A." Help yourself.
你對傑克·沃爾什瞭解多少
So, what do you know about Jack Walsh?
別  別  拜託  吸煙有害健康
Ah, no, no. Come on. Come on. Cigarettes are killers.
-女人也一樣  -那是你沒遇到對的人
- So are women. - Not the right woman.
我老婆和我關係就很好
My wife and I have a wonderful relationship.
她一直堅守在我身邊
She stuck it out with me through all of this.
是守你那幾千萬吧  真辛苦她了
Yeah, stuck it out with you and all your millions. What a trouper.
我沒有幾千萬  傑克  全捐給慈善了好嗎
I don't have millions, Jack. I gave it all to charity, remember?
自己沒留下點嗎  喬恩
You didn't keep just a little for yourself, Jon?
-就留了點逃命錢  -是哦
- I kept enough to get away and stay hidden. - Yeah, right.
我們要在芝加哥轉車
You know, we change buses in Chicago.
中間有幾小時空當
You're gonna have a couple hours.
趁這機會
You would be a better man
去看看你前妻和女兒多好
if you use that time to look up your ex-wife and daughter.
這是個好機會
It's a perfect opportunity.
別多管閒事
Why don't you mind your own business.
問你個事  為什麼九年都不見他們一面
Let me ask you this. Why is it you haven't seen them in nine years?
-為什麼  -對
- Why? - Yeah.
好好好  告訴你  真煩人
That's... Just to get you off my back, I'll tell you why.
她嫁了一個警督
She married a police lieutenant,
而我在芝加哥警局名聲又不好  行了吧
and I'm not very popular with the Chicago Police Department, okay?
為什麼你在芝加哥警局名聲不好
Why aren't you popular with the Chicago police?
那是另一碼事了
That's a whole other...
和你很熟嗎  你...簡直
What, do we know each other? Get... What a...
-為什麼  -為什麼
- Why? - Why?
你幹了什麼
What did you do?
為什麼你在芝加哥警局名聲不好
Why aren't you popular with the Chicago Police Department?
那不關你的事
That's something that really doesn't concern you.
她傷你心了嗎  傑克
She hurt you, Jack?
是
Yeah.
-抱歉  -你道什麼歉
- I'm sorry. - What are you sorry about?
-抱歉揭你傷疤了  -我哪有傷疤
- I'm sorry you're hurt. - I'm not hurt.
-你剛說她傷你心了  -我才沒傷心
- You just said you were hurt. - I'm not hurt.
你剛說你傷心了
You just said you were hurt.
我沒說我傷心了  是你說的
I didn't say I was hurt. You said I was hurt.
我問你是不是傷心了
I asked if you were hurt,
你說  對  我傷心了
and you said, "Yeah, I'm hurt."
那是  你讓我說的
That's... Because you... you made me say it.
你不那麼問我也不會說出來
You're starting to put words in my mouth.
傑克  你是個成年人了
Jack, you're a grown man.
應該知道自己要說什麼
You have control over your own words.
真他媽對
You're goddamn right I do.
送你五個字  快他媽閉嘴
So here come two words for you: Shut the fuck up!
打擾一下  沃爾什半小時前
Excuse me. Walsh called Mascone
在托萊多郊外給莫斯康打了電話
about half an hour ago from outside Toledo.
他在去芝加哥的州際巴士上
He's on an Interstate Coach Lines bus headed for Chicago.
走吧
Come on.
長官  這傢伙怎麼辦
Sir, what do we do with this guy?
放了
Let him go.
那王八蛋拿了我的煙
Son of a bitch stole my cigarettes.
你上次拍胸片是什麼時候
When's the last time you had a chest X ray?
聽說過二手煙嗎
You know about secondary smoke?
很多無辜的  健康的人
You could give people lung cancer
可能會因為你得上肺癌
wh... who are innocent and tryin' to live healthy lives.
你再睡會吧  讓我清靜一會
Why don't you just go back to sleep? Leave me alone.
想幹什麼隨便你
Do whatever you have to do.
你還是把煙掐了吧
Why don't you put the cigarette out?
你就不能消停會兒
Why don't you shut up and leave me alone?
把煙掐了吧  傑克
Put the cigarette out, Jack.
-真是個  -把煙掐了吧
- What a... - Put the cigarette out.
真他媽煩死你了
Pain in the ass this guy is.
謝謝  謝謝  我還以為你是要掐了呢
Thank you. Thank you. I thought you were putting it out.
不  誰說我要掐了
No, I'm not putting it out.
為什麼你在芝加哥警局名聲不好
Why aren't you popular with the Chicago Police Department?
希德在樓下
Sid's downstairs.
-怎麼了  -咱倆該談談了
- What's up? - I think you and I should talk.
你在這晃悠什麼  出去
What are you hangin' around for? Take a walk.
聽說有人在紐約找到馬度卡斯了
I heard somebody picked up Mardukas in New York.
早知道了  我已經在處理了
It's old news. I'm already on it.
你應該知道  如果他成了污點證人
I don't have to tell you what'll happen
會有什麼後果
if he becomes a government witness.
我保證他聯繫不到警方
I can assure you that will not be the case.
我猜你肯定派人處理了
I assumed you were taking that position,
但我是來勸你別這麼冒險的
but I am supposed to advise you against such acts.
希德尼  放輕鬆  來杯奶油蘇打
Sidney, relax. Have a cream soda.
等一會就什麼問題都沒有了
Everything is gonna be all over within a few minutes.
這些又他媽是什麼人
Who the fuck are these guys?
雙手貼在車上
Hands on the bus!
好了  腳分開
All right, spread 'em.
是他媽聯調局的人
It's the fuckin' feds.
還記得我嗎
Remember me?
墨鏡特工
Agent Foster Grant.
阿朗佐  你不該感謝我替你把活幹完了嗎
Alonzo, aren't you gonna thank me for doin' your job for you?
真謝謝你了  沃爾什
Thank you, Walsh.
快離開這  開車
Let's get the fuck outta here! Come on!
-你他媽要幹什麼  -別停下
- What the hell are you doing? - Keep moving.
別急啊  不行  別這樣
Relax. No! Come on!
快點下來
Hurry it up.
你要帶我去哪兒  天哪
What are you doin'? Are you there? God! Oh!
等等  老天爺
Wait a minute. Jesus Christ! All right.
好吧  我來了  我來了
All right! I'm comin'! I'm comin'!
快上來  上來
Come on! Come on!
來了  別急啊
I'm comin'! All right! Wait a minute!
沃爾什  你個王八蛋
Walsh, you son of a bitch!
-天哪  我的老天  -閉嘴
- God! My God! - Shut up.
-剛才是怎麼了  -閉嘴
- What the hell was that? - Shut up.
怎麼還開槍了
Wh... Why were they shooting?
那都是塞拉諾的手下
Those are Serrano's people back there.
他們不想等你進監獄
They're not waiting for you to get to jail.
那為什麼不把我交給聯調局的人
You're turnin' me in. Why are we runnin'away from the F.B.I.?
我得親自帶你回去
'Cause I gotta bring you back myself.
不然就得不到錢了
Otherwise I won't get my money.
我不可能給別人
I won't give you to the feds.
"阿朗佐·莫斯利"  這不是你假冒的特工嗎
"Alonzo Mosely." Isn't that the name you've been using?
給我瞧瞧
Let me see that.
-你看這些記錄  -怎麼了
- Look at this wealth of information. - What?
他們竊聽了莫斯康的電話
They got a tap on Mascone's line.
王八蛋
Son of a bitch!
你要幹什麼  你要幹什麼
What are ya doin'? What are ya doin'?
你覺得開著偷來的警車能跑多遠
How far do you think we're gonna get in a stolen F.B.I. car?
-這是幹什麼  -阿朗佐才懂的玩笑
- What's that for? - An inside joke between me and Alonzo.
-托尼·達爾沃在一號線  -說
- Tony Darvo, line one. - Yeah?
抱歉  吉米  搞砸了
Sorry, Jimmy. It didn't happen.
搞砸了  你再說一遍  托尼
It didn't happen? Say that again, Tony.
真搞砸了  周圍全是條子
It just didn't happen. There was cops all over the place.
來了一堆聯調局的人  吉米
There was a million fuckin' feds all over. Jimmy,
場面太亂了  真的太混亂了
it was a mess. It was a real mess.
-趕緊掛了吧  -希德尼
- You'd better get off the line. - Sidney,
他們要是竊聽了這通電話
If they've got a tap on that line...
希德尼  閉上你的臭嘴
Sidney, shut your fuckin' mouth!
聽好了  蠢貨
Now, listen to me, dummy.
他們抓到馬度卡斯了嗎
Do they have Mardukas in custody or not?
我  我  吉米  我不知道
I don't... I don't... Jimmy, I don't know.
遍地都是條子
The cops are swarming all over the place.
根本看不清人
We couldn't see anything.
你們兩個蠢貨聽好了
Let me tell you two stupid motherfuckers something.
再讓我聽到這樣的消息
I don't wanna get another phone call like this, because if I do,
我就飛過去
I'm gonna get on a fuckin' plane,
把你倆砍了當柴燒
and I'm gonna blow torch the both of you.
明白嗎
Do you understand?
你能消停會嗎  我和吉米說正事呢
Are you gonna stop? I'm on the phone talkin' to Jimmy.
別鬧
What are you doin'?
那時候在芝加哥就該殺了沃爾什
I should've killed Walsh in Chicago a long time ago.
別說話  希德尼  一個字都別說
Don't say a word to me, Sidney. Don't say a fuckin' word to me.
不然我把這電話塞你嘴裏
I'll get up and I'll bury this telephone in your head.
難以置信
I can't believe this.
我已經九年沒見他們了
I haven't seen them in nine years,
終於見到了  我卻得張口說
and the first thing out of my mouth is gonna be,
"能借我幾百塊嗎"
"Can I borrow a few hundred bucks?"
我有預感來這對你大有好處
I have a feeling this is gonna be very good for you.
你挺帥的
You look fine.
你們是誰
Who are you guys?
我是你媽媽的前夫
I'm your mother's ex-husband.
媽
Mom!
這小孩不錯
Nice kid.
-你好  蓋爾  -你好
- Hi, Gail. - Hello.
-你還好嗎  -挺好的
- How ya doin'? - I'm doin' good.
你好
Hi.
今早的新聞裏提到了你倆
They mentioned you and him on the news this morning.
-是嗎  -嗯
- They did? - Yeah.
怎麼說的  有好話嗎
What'd they say? Anything good?
沒  你沒事吧
No. Are you all right?
沒事
Yeah.
你惹了不少麻煩  傑克
You're in a lot of trouble, Jack.
我能進屋待幾分鐘嗎  蓋爾
Can I come in for a few minutes, Gail?
我能進屋待幾分鐘嗎
Can I come in for a few minutes?
進來吧
Yeah.
我不久留
I won't stay long.
不過得借你些錢去洛杉磯
I just need to borrow some money to get to L.A.
你知道我信用很好
You know I'm good for it.
傑克  家裏沒有那麼多現金
Jack, I don't think I have that kind of cash in the house.
我現在騎虎難下  處境很尷尬  蓋爾
I'm so embarrassed, I... I'm just in a jam, Gail. It...
你真漂亮
You look beautiful.
你看起來不像罪犯
You don't look much like a criminal.
-我是動腦子的罪犯  -傑森  趕緊上樓去
- I'm a white collar criminal. - Jason, go upstairs now.
傑克  你不該來這
Jack, you shouldn't be here.
要是被泰德看到了  你倆會被逮捕的
If Ted comes home, he's gonna arrest you and him.
-逮捕  -是的
- Arrest us? - Yeah.
那我們可麻煩大了
Then we'd be in a lot of trouble,
今天我可沒帶夠行賄的錢
'cause I'm afraid I'm short of bribe money.
好了  傑克  我不想和你吵  別說了
All right, Jack, don't start. Please, don't.
那個警督叫什麼來著
How is Lieutenant whatever-his-name-is?
-現在是副巡長了  -副巡長  陞官了唄
- It's captain now. - Oh, captain. Royalty.
傑克  我不想惹麻煩  請你理解我
Jack, I don't want any trouble. Do you understand that? Please.
-今天不適合說這個  真的  -別說了
- It is not a good day for this. I mean it. - Come on. Don't.
真抱歉我的逃亡日程
I'm sorry that my fugitive timetable
和你們家的社交安排衝突了
doesn't coincide with your social calendar.
-她不是這個意思  -喬恩  你別管
- I don't think she was saying that. - Listen, Jon. Stay out of this.
你還是那個臭脾氣  自己不好過
Same old Jack. You get your feelings hurt,
周圍所有人也別想好過
and then you walk around and hurt everybody else.
我真不想聽你說教
Last thing I need now is one of your lectures.
我沒有跟你說教  蠢貨
I'm not lecturing you! You stupid!
我是想保護你
I'm trying to protect you!
-得了吧  -泰德隨時都可能到家
- Aw, come on. - Ted is gonna be home any minute.
我們打算出門  今晚對我們來說很重要
We're all going out. It's an important night for us.
今晚嗎  什麼事那麼重要
Important night? What's so important about tonight?
我猜猜  今天是行賄日嗎
Let me guess. What, it's payoff night?
-好吧  夠了  滾出去  -別吵了
- All right, that's it! Get out! - Let's not fight.
我現在困在這了
Listen, I'm in a big fuckin'jam!
想借點錢把這傢伙送到洛杉磯
I need to borrow money so I can get this guy back to L.A.,
然後我他媽就洗手不幹了
and I'm out of this miserable fuckin' business forever!
你明白嗎
Can't you understand that?
你好
Hi.
丹尼絲
Denise?
都長這麼大了
You got so big.
抱歉  我得走了  抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm gonna go now. I'm sorry.
不  等等
No, hold on.
抱歉  親愛的  我們就是
I'm sorry, honey. It's just... We're havin' a...
-你幾年級了  -八年級
- What grade are you in now? - Eighth.
都八年級了啊
Are you in the eighth grade?
這有四十  我就這些現金
Here's $40. That's all I've got,
車鑰匙也給你
but these are the keys to my car.
就車道上那部旅行車
It's the station wagon in the driveway.
-我就跟泰德說車送去保養了  -好的
- I'll tell Ted that it's in the shop. - Okay.
別的等你到洛杉磯再說吧
And we'll worry about it when you get back to L.A.
他有好好照顧你嗎
So, uh, does he take good care of you?
是嗎  那就好
Yeah? Well, that's all I wanted to know.
他知道這件事了怎麼辦
So what's he gonna say about this?
-他會理解的  -他會...這就是愛
- He'll understand. - Oh, he'll... Yeah, that's love, you know?
再見  親愛的
Bye, honey.
等等
Wait.
錢不多  大概有一百八  我當保姆賺的
It isn't much. About $180 baby-sitting money.
-親愛的  我不能要  -拿著吧
-Oh, sweetheart, I can't. - Take it.
-不行  -拿著吧
- I can't. - Please.
-不行  不行  親愛的  -拿著吧
- I can't. I can't, sweetheart. - Take it.
你好  請幫我接艾迪·莫斯康
Hello. I'd like to make a collect call
是對方付費的電話
to an Eddie Mascone from a Jack Walsh.
莫斯康保釋代理
Mascone Bail Bonds.
傑裏  我是傑克  讓艾迪接電話
Jerry, Jack. Put Eddie on the phone.
艾迪  是傑克
Eddie, it's Jack.
傑克  晃悠夠了沒  你在哪兒
Jack, stop fuckin' around. Where are you?
我在哪兒
Where am I?
我在愛達荷州的博伊西市
I'm in Boise, Idaho.
不  等等  我在阿拉斯加的安克雷奇
No, wait a minute. I'm in Anchorage, Alaska.
不  不  不  等等
No, no, no, wait.
我在懷俄明州的卡斯帕
I'm in Casper, Wyoming.
我在豪生酒店的大堂
I'm in the lobby of a Howard Johnson's
胸前插著粉色的康乃馨
and I'm wearing a pink carnation.
你說什麼呢
What are you talkin' about?
我不是在和你講話  我是在和別人講話
I'm not talkin' to you. I'm talkin' to the other guys.
什麼別人
What other guys?
我給你描述一下
Well, let me describe the scene to you.
這些傢伙
There's these guys, see?
已經蹲了大概兩天了吧
They've probably been up for, like, two days.
腋臭嚴重  滿嘴咖啡味
They stink of B.O. They have coffee breath.
因為坐得太久飽受便秘煩惱
They're constipated from sittin' on their asses for so long.
他們就坐在一輛麵包車裏
They're sitting in a van,
可能就停在你辦公室的街對面
and they're probably parked right up the street from your office.
但現在你們可以捲鋪蓋回家了
But now, you guys, you're gonna have to pack up and go home,
因為你們露餡了  傻逼們
because I'm on to you, you dumb fucks.
艾迪  你的電話被竊聽了
Eddie, your phone is tapped.
我再也不會打這個電話了  去秦盧餐廳
Listen, I'm not gonna use this line anymore. Go to Chin Loo's.
五分鐘以後我打過去
I'll call you there in five minutes.
他們來不及竊聽那的電話  再見  各位
They can't run a tap that fast. So long, everybody.
請讓讓  夥計  我來接  我來接
Excuse me, buddy. I got it, I got it.
是打給我的  傑克  是你嗎
I think it's for me. Jack, that you?
立刻匯五百塊
Listen, I need you to wire me 500
到德州阿馬裏洛的西聯匯款辦事處
to the Western Union office in Amarillo, Texas, right away.
等等  坐個巴士要五百塊
Wait a minute. What do you need with $500 on a bus?
而且你他媽怎麼沒坐飛機回來
And why the fuck aren't you on a plane?
我沒告訴過你
Did it ever occur to you
我是專業人士  做事自有道理嗎
that I am a professional and that I might have my reasons?
我們改自己開車了
We are driving now.
身上的錢只夠到阿馬裏洛
I only have enough cash to get to Amarillo.
巴士沒法坐了
We had to scrap the bus.
別管巴士了  你們他媽的為什麼不坐飛機呢
Fuck the bus! I wanna know what happened to the goddamn plane!
-他不喜歡坐飛機  -他不喜歡坐飛機
- He doesn't like to fly. - He doesn't like to fly?
搞什麼飛機  聽好了  傑克
What the fuck does that mean? Listen to me, Jack!
這兩天半內你們最好給老子滾回來
You gotta be back here in less than two-and-a-half fuckin' days.
那他媽可是五十萬
A half million dollars of my money!
你他媽到底在晃悠什麼
What the fuck is goin' on there?
艾迪  艾迪  艾迪  我發誓
Eddie, Eddie, Eddie, I swear to God.
有氣別撒在我頭上
Don't start with me now,
不然老子崩了他丟沼澤裏埋了你信不
or I will shoot him and I will dump him in a fuckin' swamp!
我他媽沒心情和你吵
I am in no fuckin' mood for this.
把錢匯過來  我會把他按時帶到
Just send the money, and I'll have him back by the deadline.
-聽到了嗎  -聽到了
- You hear me? - Yes.
走吧
Let's go.
傑裏  馬上匯五百塊到德州阿馬裏洛  傑克·沃爾什的賬號
Jerry, wire $500 to Jack Walsh in Amarillo, Texas, right away.
德州的阿馬裏洛  對了
Amarillo, Texas. Now, listen, also.
讓道夫勒也過去  趕緊找他過去
Get Dorfler down there! Find him and get him down there too.
-好的  艾迪  -媽的
- You got it, Eddie. - Shit!
一個啤酒瓶掉下來
One of those bottles of beer should fall
九十六個啤酒瓶在牆頭
Ninety-six bottles of beer on the wall
九...
Nine...
九十三個啤酒瓶在牆頭
Ninety-three bottles of beer on the wall
為什麼你在芝加哥警局名聲不好
Why were you so unpopular with the Chicago Police Department?
因為你太有個性
'Cause of your personality?
剛才在你家怎麼回事  到底怎麼了
What happened back at your house? What was that all about?
你老婆嫁了個黑警察
Your wife married a corrupt police officer?
到底怎麼了
What was it all about?
整個警局都他媽被買通了
That whole fuckin' department was corrupt.
-哪都有好人和壞人  -也是
- There's good and bad everywhere, don't you think? -Yeah.
壞人滿地跑  至於好人就不知道了
Well, I'd say there's bad everywhere. Good I don't know about.
那你呢
What happened to you?
我沒拿他們的黑錢
I wouldn't go on the payroll.
什麼黑錢
What payroll?
當時我是臥底
I was workin' undercover. I was
已經成功接近這個芝加哥的大毒梟
close to this guy, this big heroin dealer in Chicago.
全城的毒品都是他供
He supplied the whole city.
花了我一年時間取得他的信任
Took me a year just to get his confidence.
我馬上要找到決定性證據了
Just when I was about to nail the son of a bitch,
我的同事
my, uh, fellow officers...
神奇地從我家裏找出了七磅的海洛因
mysteriously discovered seven pounds of heroin in my house.
所以這個大毒梟給了我兩個選擇
So this big-time drug dealer gave me a choice:
像別的警察一樣拿錢  然後跑路
Get on the payroll like everybody else, get out of town,
或者去蹲三十年監獄
or go to jail for 30 years.
我沒拿他們的黑錢
Well, I didn't get on the payroll,
所以後來我才來幹這個
and that's why I do this.
找到你這樣的罪犯  送進監獄
So when I find a criminal like you, I bring him in.
不用擔心誰收了賄賂
I don't have to worry about anybody takin'a payoff,
因為沒有別人  自己單干
because there is no anybody... there's just me.
怎麼不買個新表
Why don't you get a new watch?
等我多瞭解你一些再告訴你
I'll tell you when I know you better.
瞭解我  你什麼時候才會更瞭解我
You know me better? When are you gonna get to know me better?
我倒是會越來越瞭解你
I'll get to know you better.
-你卻不會更瞭解我  -能閉上嘴嗎
- You're not gonna get to know me better. - Will you shut up?
閉上嘴你怎麼瞭解我
That's what I mean.
咱們還剩多少錢
How much money do we have left?
-就這麼多  -就這麼多
- That's it? - That's it.
我們都要餓死了  你還拿錢去買煙
We're starvin', and you're buying cigarettes?
這是我的精神食糧
I need these cigarettes.
要點什麼隨便你  我有煙就夠了
You can have your whatever you're gonna have. I'll have this.
-先生們  來點什麼  -咖啡  謝謝
- What can I do for you boys? - Coffee, please.
-咖啡多少錢  -五十三美分
- How much is the coffee? - It's 53 cents.
-茶呢  -五十三美分
- How much is tea? - Fifty-three cents.
我喝茶吧
I'll have tea.
好的  今早特供是辣腸炒蛋
Okay, and our breakfast special today is chorizo and eggs.
辣腸炒蛋
Chorizo and eggs?
-辣腸炒蛋  是的  -那是什麼
- Chorizo and eggs. Yes. - Chorizo and eggs? What is that?
墨西哥辣腸
It's a Mexican sausage
配上炒雞蛋
mixed in with scrambled eggs,
配菜還有薯餅和吐司
and it comes with hash browns and toast.
我們不要  謝謝
We won't be havin' that. Thank you.
幾點了
What time you got?
-八點五十  -好吧  十分鐘以後
- Ten to 9:00. - All right, in 10 minutes,
咱們去西聯匯款辦事處取五百塊
we'll be at the Western Union office, we'll have 500 bucks.
想吃牛排都行  我請客
I'll buy you a juicy steak or whatever you want.
辣腸炒蛋
Chorizo and eggs.
-辣腸炒蛋  -想吃什麼都給你買
- Chorizo and eggs. - I'll get you whatever you want.
喬恩  今天的一切都是你自己造成的
You know, Jon, you're in this mess because you're in this mess.
不是我害的
I didn't put you in this mess.
-明白嗎  -好吧
- Do you understand? - Yeah.
你要不去招惹吉米·塞拉諾
If you had left Jimmy Serrano alone,
就沒有這些事了
this wouldn't be happening.
謝謝
Thank you.
我倒有個辦法
I had a way out of this, you know.
是嗎
Oh, yeah?
塞拉諾最怕什麼
What's the thing Serrano's most afraid of?
跟你結伴旅行
Goin' cross-country with you.
栽在自己人手裏
Gettin' knocked off by his own people.
我對他做過的交易瞭如指掌
What I know about his financial transactions
不僅能扳倒他
would not only put him away,
還能扳倒所有和他有關的黑幫勢力
but every Mob guy he ever did business with.
所以他才迫不及待要殺我
That's why he wants to kill me.
本來我打算把這些記錄拷到磁碟裏
I was gonna put all his records on computer disks.
等迫不得已
I figured if things got too rough,
還能用磁碟換條命
I could always trade them for my life.
然後呢
So what happened?
還沒來得及做就被捕了
What happened was I got arrested before I got a chance to do it.
你為什麼非要跟他死磕
Why didn't you just leave him alone?
你可不像那種
You don't look like the kind of guy
願意找這種麻煩的人
who would be involved in that sort of situation.
那你為什麼不拿那個大毒梟的黑錢
Why didn't you just leave that heroin dealer alone?
我可不是什麼黑幫御用會計師
I wasn't some Mob accountant.
我以為自己是為一家合法公司工作
I thought I worked in a legitimate firm.
當我發現自己工作的地方
When I found out I was managing accounts
其實是塞拉諾的皮包公司時
that were fronts for Serrano,
我可不能無動於衷
I couldn't just sit back and do nothing.
不過  喬恩  你還是拿了不屬於你的東西
Yeah, but, Jon, you still took what didn't belong to you.
你怎麼還站在他們那邊
How can you be on the side of a mobster?
我沒站在他們那邊
I'm not on the side of a mobster.
你不支持我就是站在他們那邊
You're on his side if you're not on my side.
我和誰都不一邊
I'm not on anybody's side.
跟我沒一點關係
I got nothing to do with it.
跟你關係大了去了
You got everything to do with this.
是你要抓我去坐牢  一入獄我就會被殺
You're taking me to jail, and in jail, you know I'll be killed.
-關我屁事  -關你屁事
- That's not my problem. - It's not your problem?
-你在報紙上讀過關於我的報導嗎  -讀過
- Did you read about me in the papers? - Yeah, I did.
-那時候你支持我嗎  -支持
- Were you on my side then? - Yeah, I was.
-為什麼現在不了  -因為你擋我財路了
- Then why aren't you now? - Because now you're in my way.
擋你財路  當真
I'm in your way? You mean it?
把我送進去有錢賺  你只關心這個
You want the money for turning me in because that's all you're about.
你眼裏只有錢
You're just about the fuckin' money.
喬恩  你怎麼想都行
Hey, Jon, you can think whatever you wanna think.
我無所謂
It doesn't matter to me,
反正那十萬我是拿定了
because I'm getting my 100,000 any which way you want it.
走吧
Let's go.
虛構的牛仔英雄
托尼  托尼  像不像哈珀龍·卡西迪Hey, Tony. Tony.
Hopalong Cassidy.
帶相機了嗎  給我來一張
You got your camera? Take a picture.
拜託  這是在機場買的
Come on. They got these at the airport.
回去的時候我是不是也該弄一頂
Should I get one on the way back?
別鬧了  把帽子拿開  好話不說第二遍
Come on. Put that away. I'm not gonna tell you again.
托尼  他們來了
Tony, there they are.
-別來無恙  傑克  -老天
- How you doin', Jack? - Aw, geez.
我代吉米向你問好
Jimmy sends you his regards.
別擔心  我們可不是來找你的
Don't worry, Jack. We're not here for you.
-找的是他  過來  -好吧
- We're here for him. Get over there. - No problem.
你瞪什麼呢  有話要說嗎
What are you starin' at? You gonna propose?
把槍放下  放下槍  混球們
Drop 'em! I said drop 'em, assholes!
-你們是什麼人  -你他媽又是誰
- Who the fuck are you guys? - Who the fuck are you?
你活不長了  知道自己在跟誰作對嗎
You're dead. You know who you're fuckin' with?
不  要不你告訴我
No. Why don't you tell me about it?
講話記著對著麥克風
Make sure you speak into the microphone.
馬文  馬文
Marvin! Marvin!
真聰明  傑克  把鑰匙給我
Very clever, Jack. Now, give me the keys.
快點  鑰匙給我
Come on! Give me the keys!
鑰匙
The keys.
看來是買一送一了  馬文
Looks like a package deal to me, Marvin.
該死的  你倆一起來吧
Goddamn it. Come on, both of ya.
-剛才那倆是什麼人  -馬文  算你有種
- Who the hell were those guys? - Marvin, you did it this time.
-什麼意思  -那都是僱傭殺手
- What are you talkin' about? - Those are hired killers back there.
-雇來殺誰的  -殺這個傢伙
- Hired to kill who? - Hired to kill this guy.
我  是我  是不是難以置信
Me. Me. Can you believe it?
誰雇的
Hired by who?
誰雇的  吉米·塞拉諾  就是他
Hired by who? Jimmy Serrano, that's who.
操
Oh, fuck.
他們殺他幹什麼
Why they wanna kill this guy?
你從不看報紙嗎  蠢貨
Don't you read the papers, knucklehead?
-當然看  -真受不了你們了
- Yeah, I read the fuckin' papers. - I can't take this.
讓他們跑了  灰色道奇  快去追
They got away! Gray Dodge! Get after 'em!
你他媽怎麼知道我們在哪兒
How the fuck did you know where we were?
-我受不了了  -你給我閉嘴
- I can't take this anymore. - Shut up a minute.
艾迪派你來的嗎
Did Eddie put you on this?
除了他還能有誰
Of course diid he put me on this!
那個王八蛋  你知道我和他都簽約了嗎
That son of a bitch. You know I have a contract with him?
-簽約了  -是啊  週一簽的
- You got a contract? - Yeah. I signed it on Monday.
他把我從匹茲堡叫來的  說你把這活辦砸了
He called me in Pittsburgh. He said you were fuckin' this thing up.
我  我什麼都沒辦砸
I'm... I'm not fuckin' anything up.
你兩天前不就該到洛杉磯了嗎
You should've been in L.A. two days ago.
馬文  我他媽做事自己有分寸
Marvin, don't tell me how to do my goddamn job.
我都在考慮要不要放了他
I'm half-thinkin' not to turn him in
讓艾迪自生自滅得了
just to watch Eddie go down the fuckin' toilet.
-這主意不錯  -誰跟你說話了
- See, that's a good thought. - What? Who the hell's talkin' to you?
是啊  誰他媽和你說話了
Yeah. Who the fuck's talkin' to you?
他也輪不到你來送了  傻逼  他是我的了
He's not yours to take anymore, whip-dick. He's mine.
你們聽到了嗎
Do you hear that?
操  這次又他媽是誰
Fuck. Now, who the fuck is this?
我的天
Jesus Christ!
幹點什麼  別坐著等死啊
Do something! Do something!
你倆真是我見過的最蠢的賞金獵人了
You guys are the dumbest bounty hunters I've ever seen!
你們連牛奶都送不了
You couldn't even deliver a bottle of milk!
你他媽閉嘴行嗎
Will you shut the fuck up?
他們哪兒去了
Where the hell did it go?
甩掉他們了嗎
You think we lost him?
不知道  我看不見
I don't know. I don't see anything.
肯定脫離危險了呢
I'm sure we're completely safe.
-你還好嗎  -沒事  我爽著呢
- You all right? - Yeah. I'm fine. I'm enjoying it.
-馬文  馬文  給我把槍  -門都沒有
- Marvin. Marvin, give me a gun. - No fuckin' way.
-你他媽快給我把槍  -給他把槍  馬文
- Will you give me a fucking gun? - Give him a gun! Marvin!
-別想耍花樣  傑克  -好吧  好吧
- Don't fuck me, Jack! - Yeah, yeah.
該死
Shit.
反正不是衝我來的
They're not after me.
開個玩笑  開個玩笑
Just kidding. Just kidding.
我以為你把鑰匙丟了
I thought you threw those away.
看問題要仔細  馬文  我丟的是車鑰匙
Always check the evidence. Marvin. Those were car keys.
-王八蛋  到嘴的十萬要飛了  -十萬
- Son of a bitch! There goes a hundred grand! - A hundred?
艾迪答應付你十萬
Eddie was gonna pay you a hundred?
怎麼  他說付你多少
Why? What was he gonna pay you?
兩萬五
Twenty-five.
王八蛋
That son of a bitch!
我操  傑克  你打中了
Holy shit, Jack! You got 'em!
馬文
Marvin!
你要幹什麼  傑克
What the hell are you doing, Jack?
洛杉磯見  馬文
See you in L.A., Marvin.
喬恩  喬恩
Jon! Jon!
喬恩  你他媽在哪兒呢  喬恩
Jon! Where the fuck are you, Jon?
拉我一把
Give me your hand.
太滑了  我撐不住了  快拉我一把
I'm slipping. I can't hold on. Give me your hand.
你要去哪兒
Where are you goin'?
喬恩
Jon!
太好了
Good.
-答應放我走嗎  -什麼
- Promise to let me go? - What?
你答應放我走嗎
You promise to let me go?
去你媽的
Fuck you!
-你先答應放我走  -去你媽的
- Promise to let me go. - Fuck you!
你這樣讓我很難抉擇
You're making it difficult for me to do the right thing here!
好吧  我答應你  放你走
All right. I promise. I'll let you go.
老天
Aw, geez.
-你還好嗎  -還行
- You all right? - Yeah, yeah.
-謝謝你救我一命  -謝謝你放我走
- Thanks for saving my life. - Thanks for letting me go.
我放你走  沒錯
I'll let you go, all right,
等你進了洛杉磯監獄我就放你走
the second you're in L.A. County Jail.
走吧
Come on.
沒錯  我就在這兒呢
Yeah. That's right. Down here.
你們是準備一直傻愣著
You gonna stand there with your thumb up your ass,
還是他媽把我救出去啊
or you gonna get me the fuck out of here?
剛到的消息
This just came in.
會讓我不爽嗎
Is this gonna upset me?
應該會
I think it's safe to say that.
你吃過一道菜嗎
Are you familiar with a dish...
用土豆做的...里昂土豆
a potato dish... lyonnaise potatoes?
是一種炸土豆
It's a kind of fried potato,
不過加了洋蔥
but it's got an onion in it.
特別美味
It's quite delicious.
配上牛排或是其他肉排
It really goes beautifully with, uh,
更是錦上添花
steak, uh, chops, you know,
漢堡  三明治  任何葷菜
hamburger, cheeseburger, any of your meat dishes. It's just...
我身上帶夠了買里昂那土豆的錢
You know, I have enough money to buy as much lyonnaise potatoes...
-你他媽閉嘴行嗎  -你肯定喜歡的
- Look. Just shut the fuck up, will you, please? - You really would enjoy.
我只是覺得
I just...
你應該考慮一下  因為
I think you oughta think about it a little bit, because...
等等  等等
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
謝天謝地  謝天謝地  真的太感謝了
Oh, thank you, thank you. Thank you very much.
把手銬擋上
Cover it up.
勞駕  能載我們到鎮上嗎
Hey. You think you could give us a ride to the next town?
-當然  上後面坐著吧  -多謝了
- Sure. Jump in the back. - Thanks a lot.
太好了  每倒一次霉  都有六個好人來搭救
Great, great. See? For every shit, there's six nice people.
-你們好  各位  -什麼意思
- Yahe, everyone. Yahe. - What's that?
"你好"的意思  我會不少語言的問候語
It's "Hello." I can say "Hello" in a lot of different languages.
雖然跟你沒法溝通
Not yours, but a lot of them.
歡迎光臨  先生
Welcome, sir.
-我可沒料到會到這一步  -你當我願意嗎
- I'm not lookin' forward to this. - You think I am?
你倆是有多無能
I don't understand the problem with you two.
他他媽就是個會計
The guy's a fuckin' accountant.
吉米  我們運氣實在不好
Jimmy, it's been bad luck right down the line.
而且那個沃爾什也不好對付
Plus, this guy Walsh is pretty good.
他真那麼厲害嗎  托尼
If he's that good, Tony,
我該雇他來殺了你們
maybe I should hire him to hit you.
希望條子不會反查到吉米身上
I hope there's no chance of any of this comin' back to Jimmy.
不可能  直升機是從堪薩斯租來的
No chance. We rented the chopper out of Kansas City.
和你八竿子打不著
It's five times removed from you,
你絕對沒事  別擔心
so you're clear of this. Don't worry.
沒事個屁  你個傻逼
Clear as shit, you fuckin' moron!
那傢伙還活得好好的  不是嗎
The guy's still out there, ain't he?
你倆聽好了
Let me tell you two guys somethin'.
這次要再殺不掉那個會計
I'm not interested in seeing either one of you two alive again
就甭想活著見我了  懂嗎
until you get the accountant. You got the message?
-下車吧  -就到這嗎
- It's the end of the ride. - This is it?
就到這
This is it.
這附近有什麼大的鎮子嗎
Is there a real town around here someplace?
-錢寧  -錢寧
- Channing's. - Channing's?
離這兒多遠
How far is that from here?
-三十英里  -三十英里  老天爺
- Thirty miles. - Thirty miles. Oh, Jesus Christ.
這也好意思叫鎮子
What the hell kind of town is this?
你們中有誰能載我們到錢寧嗎
Is there someone that could give us a ride to Channing?
-有人要往那個方向去嗎  -不  沒人去
- Is there anyone going in that direction? - No. No have a ride.
打擾一下  這裏有廁所嗎
Excuse me a minute. Is there a bathroom in there I could use?
去吧
Yeah. Go ahead.
這裏有電話嗎  電話
Is there a telephone here? Telephone?
不  不  沒有電話
No. No. No telephone.
沒有電話  什麼都沒有
No telephone? Nothing?
真高興能逗你們一笑
Yeah. Glad you're having a good time.
"恐飛癥"  你個王八蛋
"Fear of flying"? You son of a bitch!
給老子回來  回來  你個狗娘養的
Get over here! Get back here, you son of a bitch!
給老子回來  停下
Get over here! Stop!
停下
Stop!
恐飛你大爺  狗娘養的
Fear of flying, my ass, you son of a bitch.
給老子從飛機上下來
Get out of that plane!
你個王八蛋還會開飛機
You're a goddamn pilot, you son of a bitch?
我覺得這事告訴你不太好  傑克
I didn't feel it was appropriate to share that with you, Jack.
揍你一頓好不好  他媽的
I'm gonna fuckin' "appropriate" your head, goddamn it!
怎麼停下這該死的飛機
How do you turn this fuckin' thing off?
-抓穩了  -熄火  快熄火
- Hang on! - Turn it off! Turn it off!
抓穩了  我要慢慢降下來
Hang in there. I'm gonna let it down easy.
他媽的  快停下
Goddamn it! Turn this fuckin' thing off!
糟糕
Oh, shit!
你他媽會開飛機  你個飛行員
You're a goddamn pilot? You're a pilot? Yeah.
我讓你飛
I'll show you pilot.
我給你說說我把你送進去以後
Let me tell you about the coffee shop
拿了十萬塊開的咖啡店吧
I'm gonna open after I dump you and get my hundred grand.
你會喜歡的
You're gonna love it.
好了  後退  後退  後退
All right. Get back. Get back. Get back.
所有人後退
Everybody, back.
把卡車的鑰匙給我
Give me the keys to the truck.
你不能偷他們的卡車
You can't steal their truck.
閉嘴  你剛剛才偷了他們的飛機
Shut up! You were about to steal a plane.
-你也好意思說  -我只是想救自己一命
- What are you talkin' about? - I was trying to save my life.
說的對  是應該給人家點補償
You're right. I should give 'em somethin'.
把你的表拿來
Give me your watch.
-我的表  該死  -把表給我
- My watch? Shit! - Give me your watch!
拿著  值不少錢呢  上車
Keep it. It's worth a lot of money. Get in.
退後  進去
Stand back! Get in.
進去
Get in!
傑克  咱們捋捋清楚  是你先騙我的
Jack, let's be fair about this. You lied to me first.
-在  在河邊  -什麼
- At... At the river, - what?
-在河邊  在  -閉上你的
- At the river, before... - Get the fu...
-在河邊  -你先騙我的...
- At the river... - You lied to...
你先騙我的  騙起人來眼都不眨
You lied to me first. You got some fuckin' nerve.
不  你先騙我的
No. You lied to me first!
你先騙我的
You lied to me first!
沒錯  沒錯  是我先騙你的
Yes. Yes, I lied to you first,
但在河邊的時候你還不知道
but you had no knowledge I was lying about my fear of flying
我說我有恐飛癥是騙你的
at the river when you lied to me.
所以站在你的角度  還是你先騙我的
So as far as you knew, you lied to me first.
懶得和你爭
I can't even argue with you.
我他媽都聽不懂你在說什麼了
I don't even know what the fuck you're talkin' about.
就是在你不知情的前提下  是你先騙了我
I'm just saying you lied to me first as far as you knew.
-天哪  -怎麼了
- Jesus. - What's the matter?
-胃潰瘍犯了  -胃潰瘍
- I got an ulcer. - An ulcer?
對  潰瘍犯了  胃裏一大塊潰瘍
Yeah, I got an ulcer. I got a big fuckin' ulcer.
托你的福又開始流血了
All your bullshit's starting to make it bleed again.
知道自己為什麼會得胃潰瘍嗎
You know why you have an ulcer?
因為你就只會兩種表達方式
'Cause you have two forms of expression:
沉默和憤怒
silence and rage.
你應該喝點牛奶緩解一下
You should get some milk to coat it.
不用你多事
Don't tell me what I need.
吃點東西就好了
I need something to eat, that's what I need.
可我們用什麼買呢  泥巴嗎
What are we gonna buy it with? Dirt?
開到下個城鎮  我來搞定
You drive to the next town. I'll take care of it.
-你來搞定  -我來搞定
- You'll take care of it? - I'll take care of it.
-你準備怎麼搞定  -到了就知道了
- What do you mean you'll take care of it? - Drive to the next town.
但還是你先騙我的
But you lied to me first.
老紅酒吧
顧客泊車處
-現在怎麼辦  -把你聯調局那個證件給我
- Now what? - Give me that F.B.I. badge.
聯調局的證件
The F.B.I. badge?
對  給我
Yeah. Give me the F.B.I. Badge.
把銬子解了
Uncuff me.
-把銬子解了  -把銬子解了
- Uncuff me? - Uncuff you.
想吃東西嗎  想好好吃一頓嗎
Do you wanna eat? Want a nice meal?
想吃點好的嗎
Want some of that shit you eat?
來吧  把銬子解了
Come on. Uncuff me.
你要敢耍花樣
You fuck with me...
就把我揍得屁滾尿流再丟進沼澤
You'll hit me on the head and drop me in a thing.
知道了  快  給我解開
Right. Come on. Uncuff me.
-這兒誰管事  -誰想知道
- Who's in charge here? - Who wants to know?
-我  -當然是經理
- Me. - That'd be the manager.
-我要見他  越快越好  -好的  警官
- I'd like to see the manager as soon as possible. - Yes, sir.
抱歉
Sorry.
有事嗎
Yeah?
我是聯調局特工阿朗佐·莫斯利
Alonzo Mosely, F.B.I.
有個散佈二十元假鈔的造假團伙
My partner and I have been tracking counterfeiters
我和我的搭檔正在調查
passing phony $20 bills across state.
近幾小時內你有收到二十元的鈔票嗎
Have you received any $20 bills in the last couple of hours?
當然  我們經常收到
Yeah, sure. We get 'em all the time.
你們經常收到
You get 'em all the time.
能麻煩你後退兩步嗎
Would you mind taking two steps backwards?
你能把收銀櫃打開嗎
Would you mind opening the register?
不  你別動
No. Don't touch 'em.
借用一下
Excuse me.
二號條款  漢克  檢查一下
Contract two, Hank. Check 'em out.
請給他一支鉛筆
Give him a pencil, please.
做石蕊檢驗
Do the litmus configuration.
你做的是石蕊測試嗎
You doing the litmus configuration?
-石蕊測試  -沒錯
- The litmus configururation. - Yes.
-你在附近見過什麼可疑的人嗎  -沒
- You seen any suspicious-looking characters around here? - No.
-你住在附近嗎  -是的
- Do you live around here? - Yeah.
-怎麼樣  -這張是假鈔
- How's it look? - This one's bad.
請你詳細描述一下
Would you describe exactly what the last man
之前給你二十元鈔票的人的外貌
who passed a $20 bill to you looked like?
-大約三十歲  很高  -有六英尺高嗎
- Thirty. Tall. - About six feet tall?
-六尺五吧  -深棕色頭髮
- Six-five. - Dark brown hair?
淺棕色
Light-colored.
-聽著像是他  -就是他
- Sounds like our man. - That's him.
鈔票我們要留作證據
We're gonna have to take these bills for evidence.
給他開張收據
Make up a receipt.
-這張也是假的  -這張也是假的
- This one's bad too. - This one's bad too.
請你通知周邊所有業主
I'd like you to notify all the establishments in the area.
-你的酒吧叫什麼名字  -老紅酒吧
- What's the name of your establishment? - Red's Corner Bar.
-你是老紅  -是的  警官
- Are you Red? - Yes, sir.
-你把紅髮染了嗎  -沒啊
- You dye your hair? - No.
他們為什麼叫你老紅
Why do they call you Red?
是紅木的簡稱  我姓木
It's short for redwood. My last name's Wood.
-你叫什麼  -比爾
- What's your first name? - Bill.
感謝你的合作  比爾  漢克
Thank you for your cooperation, Bill. Hank.
這些是假的  那些是真的
These are all bad. Those are good.
-來吧  我們得上這列車  -什麼
- Come on. We're gonna get this train. - What?
我們登上去  走吧
We're gonna catch this train. Come on.
我可追不上火車
I can't catch a train.
你還說不能坐飛機呢  跑起來  走吧
You also couldn't fly. Start runnin'. Let's go.
等等  這是貨運火車啊
Wait. It's a freight train!
-我跑不動了  我跑不動了  -快跑
- I can't do this! I can't do this! - Come on.
我真心覺得我跑不動了
I deeply feel I can't do this!
你不是說喜歡坐火車嗎  給我上去
I thought you loved to travel by train. Get up there!
-你幹什麼  -不是說好放我走的嗎
- What are you doin'? - Do you promise to let me go?
給我打開這該死的門
Open the fuckin' door!
下輩子見  傑克
See you in the next life, Jack!
你個王八蛋
You son of a bitch!
狗娘養的  把這該死的門打開
You son of a bitch, open that fuckin' door!
看見我很高興吧
Huh. Glad to see me?
我猜現在是下輩子了吧  喬恩
Huh? I guess we're in the next life, Jon.
不要激動
Don't overreact now.
"不要激動"  老子才不激動  給老子過來
"Don't overreact." I won't overreact! Get over here!
激動  再敢這樣  老子直接把你丟下車
React? You do this again, I'll throw you off the fuckin' train!
傑克  這不是個好
Jack, it's a bad...
把手放那兒  手放那兒
Put your hand in there! Put your hand in there!
-好吧  好吧   -淡定  傑克  淡定
- All right. All right. - Easy, Jack. Easy, easy.
待著吧  你個王八蛋
There, you son of a bitch!
傑克
Jack?
給老子閉嘴  我他媽一句話也不想和你說了
You shut up! I'm not talkin' to you for the whole rest of this trip!
你們還準不準備放我了
Are you guys gonna let me go or what?
我說了我什麼都不知道
I'm tellin' you, I don't know anything.
真的嗎
Is that a fact?
該死
Oh, shit.
你還是戒煙吧  也能給我省點錢
Why don't you quit? It'd be cheaper for both of us.
他們在哪兒
Where are they?
問倒我了
You got me.
-警探...  -閉嘴
- Inspector... - Shut up.
聽著  混蛋  我現在就要答案
Now, you listen, you son of a bitch. I want answers right now.
什麼答案  我什麼都不知道啊
What do you want from me? I don't know nothin'.
長官
Sir,
有人報案說阿朗佐·莫斯利特工
it seems that an Agent Alonzo Mosely
與其搭檔在錢寧附近跳上一列
and his partner were seen
西行的貨運列車
hopping a westbound freight train near Channing.
走吧
Come on.
傑克  "幹什麼"
Jack? "What?"
我們還得坐多遠
How much further do you think we have to go?
"關你屁事"
"None of your fuckin' business."
不是  因為  那個
No. Because, you know,
我總得上個廁所吧
eventually I'm going to have to go to the bathroom.
"把嘴閉上"
"Shut the fuck up. "
你和動物搞過嗎  傑克
Did you ever have sex with an animal, Jack?
記得印第安保留區的那些雞嗎
Remember those chickens around Indian reservation?
說實話  長得還挺好看  傑克
There were some good-looking chickens. Jack.
就跟你說說
You know, between us.
是啊  我看有幾隻我還挺有戲的
Yeah. There were a couple there I might've taken a shot at.
你和那塊表到底有什麼故事
What's with you and that watch?
這表到底是什麼來歷
What is it with the watch?
你說等你更瞭解我了就告訴我
You told me when you get to know me better.
你都說了雞的事了
You told me about your feelings for chickens.
表的故事能有多隱私呢
How private could the watch be?
到底是什麼大秘密
What's the big secret?
這表是蓋爾買來送我的
Gail bought me this watch. She gave it to me.
是她送我的第一個禮物
It was the first thing she ever gave me.
她送我這塊表  因為我經常遲到
She... She bought it because I was always late,
每次都有半個小時吧
at least a half an hour or so.
她把表調快了半小時
She bought it and set it ahead a half an hour
這樣我就不會遲到了
so I'd never be late.
我內心深處
Somewhere in the back of my mind,
總覺得我們有一天能重修舊好
I keep thinkin' we're gonna wind up together again.
我也不懂自己還堅持什麼
I don't know why I'm still hangin' on,
還在等什麼
I'm still waitin' around.
她不會回來了
I don't think she's comin' back.
是啊  我也這麼想  我也這麼想
Yeah. I don't either. I don't either.
有時你得學會放手
Sometimes you just have to let go.
買塊新表吧
Just get yourself a new watch.
你人不錯  傑克
You're okay, Jack.
咱倆就算不這麼相遇
I think, under different circumstances,
可能也會恨對方
you and I probably still would've hated each other.
也沒準能做朋友
Yeah. We probably could've been friends.
下輩子吧
In the next life.
是啊  下輩子吧
Yeah, the next life.
真棒  你們這兒食宿條件真不錯
Yeah. Great. The accommodations were wonderful.
-有煙嗎  -不抽
- You got a smoke? - Don't smoke.
-那個聯調局的拿了我的煙  -想拿回你的煙
- That fed took my cigarettes. - You want your cigarettes back?
那你得去弗拉格斯塔夫了
Then you're gonna have to go to Flagstaff to get 'em,
莫斯利那傢伙也去了那兒
'cause that's where your pal Mosely went.
我沒準真會去呢
Just might do that.
咱們到哪兒了
Where do you figure we are?
差不多該到亞利桑那了
My guess would be Arizona.
整夜西行  應該快到家了
We've been goin' west all night. I think we're almost home.
我也離死不遠了
I'm almost dead.
喬恩  證人保護計劃也沒那麼糟糕
Look, Jon. You know, the witness protection program isn't so bad.
他們會給你新的身份  新的生活
They'll give you a new name. You'll have a new life.
我可活不到什麼證人保護計劃
I'm not gonna make it to any witness protection program.
-誰知道呢  喬恩  -你心知肚明
- You don't know that, Jon. - I know that and you know that.
等不到我申請到證人保護
Serrano's going to get to me before I get to
塞拉諾就能殺了我
any witness protection program.
行行好  別假裝在乎我了
Do me a favor. Don't pretend you care about me.
簡直是侮辱我的智商
It really insults my intelligence.
咱倆都面對現實吧
I mean, let's face it.
我對你唯一的用處  就是賺錢
The only important thing about me to you, is gettin' your money.
你能不能別老把我看成一個
I'm tired of you makin' me out to be some kind of thug
滿腦子銅臭的大老粗
whose only concern is a big chunk of change.
你知不知道塞拉諾的手下
Did you know that Serrano's people
出價一百萬讓我把你交出去
offered me a million bucks for you?
你還不如答應他們呢
Why don't you go over to big money?
反正我最後還是得落到他手裏
You're doin' his work for him anyway.
落到他手裏
I'm working for him anyway?
你他媽什麼也不明白
You don't know what the fuck you're talkin' about.
我接這活最根本的原因
The reason I do this shit in the first place
就是不想幫那個人渣做事
is 'cause I wouldn't work for that lowlife asshole.
什麼意思
What does that mean?
沒什麼  不重要
Nothin'. Doesn't mean anything.
塞拉諾是你口中的芝加哥大毒梟
Serrano is the heroin dealer you told me about in Chicago?
買通你同事  毀了你生活的就是塞拉諾
Who owned your buddies and destroyed your life? That's Serrano?
那你還打算把我送進監獄
That's the guy that you're takin' me in...
好讓他來殺了我
That's the guy that's gonna kill me?
希望那家咖啡館真的物有所值  傑克
I hope it's a wonderful coffee shop, Jack.
-走吧  該下車了  -幹什麼  什麼
- Come on. We're gettin' off. - What? What? What?
-該走了  火車男  來吧  -不
- We are getting off here, Mr. Railroad Man. Come on. - No.
拜託  你瘋了嗎  拜託  先商量下行嗎
Come on! What are you talking about? Come on! Let's discuss this!
-找到了嗎  -還沒
- You find anything? - Not yet.
他們可能在沿線任何地方跳車
They could've jumped off the train anywhere along the line.
火車沿線會有一個個車站
Trains have regularly scheduled stops.
設置車站就是為了
The reason for that is you know,
讓人們在停車時能夠安全下車
because people plan to get off the trains when they stop,
所以正常人都會在車站下車
and that's how, generally, people do it.
而不是在列車行駛時把別人扔下去
They don't throw each other off the trains.
所以才有車站
That's the purpose of having stops.
這是要幹什麼  你要幹什麼  你又幹什麼
What's this? What are you gonna do? What are you doing now?
你要幹什麼  你要幹什麼
What are you doing? What are you doing?
天哪  天哪  拜託  你開玩笑的吧
Oh, Christ. Christ. Come on. Come on. You kidding?
我們會被打成馬蜂窩的  老天爺
They're gonna come out and shoot us, for Chrissake!
搞什麼  搞什麼
What the hell. What the hell.
老天  這下好了
Jesus. Oh, great.
你負責發動車子
You get it started,
我把你撞飛
and I'll run you over.
這是我能想到的最好的主意了
That's the best plan I can think of.
恭喜  恭喜
Congratulations. Congratulations.
-又多了一條罪名  -走吧
- Another crime. - Come on.
我很反感  很反感所有你做的事
I don't like this. I don't like anything you do,
實話告訴你  沒一件喜歡的
to tell you the truth. Nothin'.
-我們去哪兒  -最近的機場
- Where are we going? - To the nearest airport.
我都懶得當事後諸葛亮了
I'm not the kind of guy that says, "I told you so."
糟糕
Oh, shit!
他們在這裏以南三十五英里的
Looks like they've been spotted
塞多那附近被發現
around 35 miles south of here, near Sedona.
已經有警官在進行追捕
There are officers in pursuit.
我們坐直升機走
Let's take the chopper.
這  這  看這樣子
This is... This is... This is the kind of situation
咱們要糟
where something bad happens.
慢點
Easy!
該死  我討厭這樣
Goddamn it! I don't like this!
卡車  卡車
Truck! Truck!
-你要去哪兒  傑克  -到了就知道了
- Where you going, Jack? - You'll find out when we get there.
我陷得太深  太深
I've come too far. Too far.
離終點又如此的近
Come too close.
好了  我來了  好了
Okay. I'm coming. All right.
-走吧  -好吧
- Come on. - Right.
運氣不錯  你好
Here we go. Hello.
你好
Hello.
是我走運了還是我太厲害了
Am I lucky, or am I just good?
-那是馬文嗎  -那還用說  老子當然是最棒的
- Is that Marvin? - Fuckin' "A". I'm the best.
-馬文  -你好啊  傑克  你個傻逼
- Marvin? - Hello, Jack, you dumb shit.
老天
Jesus!
-過來  你個王八蛋  -等等  等等
- Come on, you fuckin' pain in the ass. - Hold on. Wait a minute.
敢動一下撕了你
If you move, I'll tear your fuckin' lungs out.
洛杉磯見  傑克
See you in L.A., Jack.
媽的
Shit.
-下午好  先生  -下午好
- Afternoon, sir. - Afternoon.
-還開業嗎  -我們全天營業
- You're open? - Oh, we're always open.
今天挺難熬的
Hard day, huh?
-這一周都糟透了  -看得出來
- Hard week. - Yeah, I know what you mean.
給我來杯咖啡吧
I could use a cup of coffee.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
-謝謝  -不客氣
- Thanks. - You welcome.
拿著吧
Keep 'em.
天哪  我找了好久
Gee. I've been lookin' all over for these.
謝了  阿朗佐
Thanks, Alonzo.
馬文  我得提醒你一下
Marvin, I have to tell you,
我患有嚴重的恐飛癥
I have this very serious fear of flying.
是嗎  那就放輕鬆  睡過去吧
Yeah? Well, why don't you just relax and sleep through it.
忘了截止日期吧  沃爾什
Forget your deadline, Walsh.
這個案子對你來說已經結束了
It's over. That's the way that one went.
我知道我有什麼權利  我要打電話
I know my rights. You owe me phone calls.
現在你的當務之急可不是
What should be of paramount importance to you right now
打電話
is not the phone calls.
是你因為假扮特工
It's the fact that you're gonna
要去坐的那十年牢
spend 10 years for impersonating a federal agent.
-假扮特工要判十年嗎  -十年
- Ten years for impersonating a fed, huh? - Ten years.
十年  那怎麼沒人來抓你呢
Ten years. How come no one's after you?
-讓他打電話  -謝了
- Give this guy his calls. - Thanks.
能給我點私人空間嗎
Can I have a little privacy, please?
莫斯康保釋代理
Mascone Bail Bonds.
-我是傑克·沃爾什  讓艾迪接  -是傑克
- Yeah. It's Jack Walsh. Put Eddie on. - It's Jack.
你最好告訴我些好消息
Yeah. This better be good news,
傑克  因為只剩五個小時了
fuckin' Jack, because you got five hours left.
不  你想多了  艾迪  我就是告訴你
No,it's not, Eddie. I'm calling to let you know
你他媽就等死吧
that you're a dead motherfucker, you understand me?
等等  等等
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
我的活你敢讓馬文來摻合  王八蛋
You put Marvin on this case, you fuckin' piece of shit?
-你個殺千刀的騙子  人渣  -罵夠沒
- You fucking, deceptive... You vermin! - You fuckin' done yet?
-你他媽就是屎裏的蛆  -是你搞砸了  好嗎
- You slimeball in a sea of pus! What? - You blew it, all right?
你抓到那傢伙都他媽四天了  傑克  四天了
You had the guy four fuckin' days, Jack. Four days!
你他媽
You could've fuckin'...
就他媽倒著走也走回來了吧
You could've walked him backwards and not fuckin' blown it.
就這樣你都搞砸了
But you blow it!
我他媽以前做事讓你失望過嗎  你個小人
When have I ever... When have I ever let you down, you fuckin' rat?
你瘋了嗎  跑去告訴道夫勒我付你十萬
Are you fuckin' nuts, tellin' Dorfler I offered you $100,000,
我跟他說只給他兩萬五
when I told him I'd give him 25,000?
等等  等一下
Wait a minute. Wait, wait.
-你什麼時候和他聯繫過  -重要嗎
- When did you speak to him? - What's the difference?
你什麼時候和馬文聯繫過
When did you speak to Marvin?
大概  十分鐘之前
He called me fuckin', what, 10 minutes ago,
也是大吼大叫  讓我滾他媽的蛋
yellin' and screamin', tellin' me to go fuck myself.
你也跟我說  怎麼誰都讓我滾他媽的蛋
You're tellin' me... Everybody's tellin' me to go fuck myself!
-什麼  -我他媽長得像足球嗎
- What? - Am I supposed to just sit on my fuckin' butt?
艾迪  艾迪  艾迪  艾迪
Eddie, Eddie, Eddie, Eddie.
-你他媽說什麼呢  -你還剩五個小時
- What are you fuckin' talkin' about? - Look, you got five hours left.
能把"公爵"帶回來嗎  給個准話
Can you bring the fuckin' Duke in, yes or no?
不是在他手上嗎
I thought he's bringing him to you.
我剛和道夫勒通過電話
I just talked to fuckin' Dorfler.
-"公爵"不在他手上  -什麼
- He don't have the Duke. - What?
-該死的"公爵"在哪兒  人呢  -再聯絡
- Where's the fuckin' Duke? Hello? - I'll talk to you later.
傑克
Jack?
托尼·達爾沃
-你好  -我找托尼·達爾沃
- Hello? - Is Tony Darvo there, please?
-你是誰  -馬文·道夫勒
- Who's calling? - Marvin Dorfler.
馬文·道夫勒打電話來了
Yo. I got Marvin Dorfler on the line.
-要幫你接通嗎  -好  好  接過來
- Shall I put him through? - Yeah, yeah, yeah. Put him through.
馬文  一切還在按計劃進行嗎  夥計
Marvin, everything's still on schedule, pal, isn't it?
-原來道夫勒改給你們賣命了  -你是誰
- So Dorfler's working for you guys? - Who is this?
-傑克·沃爾什  -傑克  你在抱怨什麼呢
- This is Jack Walsh. - Jack. What are you complainin' for?
我們先找的你  不是嗎  是傑克·沃爾什
We came to you first, didn't we? It's Jack Walsh.
等一下  有人想給你問個好
Hold on. Somebody wants to say hello.
過期不候了  傻逼
Hey. Too late for you, scumbag.
不  不  這話應該我說
No, no. Too late for you.
我沒拿到錢可不會善罷甘休
I didn't come this far not to collect my money,
聽明白了嗎  王八蛋
you understand me, you motherfuckers.
-我是來要人的  -跟我說幹什麼
- I want the Duke back. - So what the fuck you tellin' me for?
跟你說幹什麼  跟你說幹什麼
What am I tellin' you for? What am I tellin' you for?
我  我告訴你跟你說幹什麼
What am I... I'll tell you what I'm tellin' you for.
就因為我這有一些"公爵"的東西
I got some of the Duke's belongings, that's why,
包括電腦磁碟什麼的
including some computer disks
記錄了塞拉諾非法交易
that have every last detail of Serrano's businesses
和洗錢流程的每一筆賬  應有盡有
and his money-laundering operations. Everything.
兩小時內不把"公爵"還給我
If I don't get the Duke back in two hours,
我就把磁碟交給調查局的人
I'm gonna turn those disks over to the feds.
聽到沒  告訴塞拉諾兩小時內
Do you hear me? You tell Serrano I wanna meet him
帶著"公爵"到
with the Duke, alone, in two hours
麥卡倫機場的主航站樓
in the main terminal at McCarran Airport
在那做交易
where we'll make the exchange.
你們那群傻逼裏面
I know he's the only one of you idiots
就他不敢在公共場合對我動手
who won't try to take a shot at me in public place.
我看到他一個手下
And if I see one fuckin' single goon
出現在機場周圍
within a mile of that airport,
聽清楚了
and listen to me very carefully,
交易立馬取消  我直接去找條子
the deal is off, and I'm going to the feds.
我不會跟吉米說你的這些瞎話
I ain't gonna bother Jimmy with your bullshit.
是嗎  那敢情好  你可千萬別說
Oh, yeah? You're not? Ok, fine, fine.
等他被捕了
After he's busted,
我一定第一時間讓他知道我告訴過你
I'll make sure to let him know you knew all about it beforehand.
兩小時內  麥卡倫機場的主航站樓
That's two hours from now, main terminal, McCarran Airport.
聽清了嗎  蠢貨  祝你愉快
You got that, moron? Have a nice day.
跟阿朗佐說我想做個交易
Tell Alonzo I wanna make a deal.
你想和我做交易
You wanna make a deal with me?
把塞拉諾交給你怎麼樣
What would you do if I could deliver you Serrano?
怎麼個交法
What do you mean "deliver"?
至少可以控告他企圖銷毀政府證物
For starters, conspiracy to destroy government evidence.
什麼政府證物
What government evidence?
能讓我親自帶"公爵"回去拿錢嗎
Will you let me take the Duke back myself and collect my money?
-說詳細點  -路上說
- Tell me more. - I'll have to tell you on the way.
咱們得在兩小時內到拉斯維加斯
Because we gotta be in Las Vegas in two hours.
藍天使汽車旅館
有空房
馬文
Marvin?
-馬文  -不  客房服務
- Marvin? - No. It's room service.
拿著這個  這樣就知道是今天拍的了
Here. Hold this up so they know I took this today.
是不是很聰明  我的大腦總是運轉如飛
I amaze myself. I'm always thinkin'.
沒有我解決不了的問題
Got it all figured out.
-說"茄子"  -別這麼做  馬文
- Now, say "Cheese". - Don't do this, Marvin.
再見
Adios.
-根本沒有什麼電腦磁碟  對嗎  -對
- There are no real computer disks. Is that right? - Right.
他動手接了你手裏的空磁碟
So if you give him blank disks and he accepts them,
才構成犯罪嗎
would that be considered an overt act?
只要他踏入機場
If he just sets foot inside the airport,
就已經構成犯罪條件了
he's committed an overt act.
這叫企圖妨礙司法公正
Conspiracy to obstructjustice.
他要和"公爵"一起出現  你還能告他綁架
When he shows up with the Duke, you add kidnapping.
他的人如果帶了槍  就告他謀殺
Anybody packing a gun, conspiracy to commit murder.
因為是在機場
The fact that it's an airport...
阿朗佐  我說錯你就指出來
Alonzo, correct me if you think I'm wrong,
我不是搶你生意
I don't want to step on your toes,
哪怕是現在  他都算是跨州窩藏逃犯
you can slap an interstate transportation, aid of racketeering rap
還有協助敲詐罪
on him right away as well.
如果你不能讓他拿走磁碟
None of that bullshit means anything
剛才這一堆都是白扯
unless you can get him to take those disks from you.
別擔心  我會讓他拿到磁碟的
Don't worry. I'll get him to take the disks.
在他身上裝個竊聽器
Get a wire on this man.
馬文
Marvin.
阿馬裏洛那點小誤會希望你們別介意
Hey, no hard feelings about what happened back in Amarillo, huh?
那時候是形勢所迫
It's just one of those spur-of-the-moment deals, you know?
-他在哪兒  -錢在哪兒
- Where is he? - Where's the money?
車裏  他在哪兒
In the car. Where is he?
我改主意了  現在要兩百萬了
Slight change of plans. Now I want two million.
-什麼  -我回去讀了報紙
- What? - Hey. I read the newspapers, you know?
這傢伙拿了你們一千五百萬  是嗎
The guy got you for 15 million, right?
我想他至少值兩百萬
So I figure the guy's gotta be worth at least two.
我是個生意人
I'm a businessman.
我們怎麼知道他在你手裏
How do we know you got him?
現在給我一百萬  二十分鐘後給你電話
I want one million now, and I'll call you in 20 minutes,
告訴你另外一百萬放哪兒
tell you where to drop off the second million.
我拿到錢就告訴你們他在哪兒  行不
Once I know it's there, then I'll tell you where he is. Okay?
-不行  -為什麼
- Not okay. - Why not?
你瘋了嗎  怎麼跟吉米交代
What? Are you fuckin' nuts? What's Jimmy gonna say?
現在我們他媽上哪兒找"公爵"去
How the fuck are we gonna get the Duke now?
答案就在你手裏
You got the answer right in your hand.
什麼意思
What are you talkin' about?
那張照片  喬伊  你什麼時候能動動腦
The paper. Joey, when are you gonna learn how to pay attention?
藍天使汽車旅館
看見寫的什麼了嗎
Look. See what it says there?
好了  就這樣
All right. This is it.
今晚要了結一切  明白嗎
Tonight is the fuckin' night, you understand?
我受不了那些廢物了
I'm sick of all of these screwups.
一旦我搶到那些磁碟
As soon as I get the disks from Walsh,
立馬殺了沃爾什和"公爵"
you guys drop Walsh and you drop the Duke.
明白嗎  一拿到磁碟就動手
Do you understand? I get the disks, you drop them. Okay?
-我不建議你這麼做  -是嗎
- I don't think you should do this. - Oh, really?
那你說我該怎麼辦
What do you propose that I do?
派人送錢給他  而不是殺了他
Send somebody with cash offer, but don't do this.
我瞭解沃爾什  他才不會收我的錢
I know Walsh. He won't take any money from me.
他正義感特別強烈  所以我才煩他
He's a very self-righteous type of guy, it aggravates me.
在他心裏  這才叫兩不相干
In his mind, this is clean.
我走我的陽關道  他過他的獨木橋
He gets what he wants; I get what I want.
-這傢伙腦子燒壞了  希德尼  -吉米  聽我說
- The guy's a fuckin' burnout, Sidney. - Hey, Jimmy, listen.
希德尼  坐下  放鬆  吃個三明治
Sidney. Sit down. Relax. Have a sandwich.
喝杯牛奶  別煩我就行
Drink a glass of milk. Do some fuckin' thing.
他出發了
He's on his way.
他在拉斯維加斯大道上向北行駛
He's heading north on Las Vegas Boulevard,
離機場約有兩英里
approximately two miles from the airport.
-繼續跟蹤  -你笑什麼
- We're right on him. - Why are you smilin'?
找回了點當警察的感覺
I feel like a cop again.
大人物終於肯露面了呀
So, I'm finally in the presence of greatness, huh?
"公爵"
The Duke.
從罪大惡極的人渣手裏偷了錢
The guy that steals money from the scum of the earth
去救濟窮苦大眾的大盜
and gives it to the unfortunates of the world.
早就想和你面對面聊聊了
I wanted to meet you face-to-face.
你真以為拿了我的錢
Did you actually think that you were gonna steal my money
還能一走了之嗎
and get away with it?
告訴你兩件事
I stopped by here to tell you two things.
第一  今晚就是你的死期
Number one is that you're gonna die tonight.
第二  我會回到家
Number two, I'm gonna go home,
飽餐一頓
have a nice hot meal,
然後找到你老婆  送她去見你
I'm gonna find your wife and I'm gonna kill her too.
喬伊  在這等我信號  其他人跟我進去
Joey, wait here for my call. The rest of you, start headin' in.
遵命
You got it.
他來了
Here he comes.
傑克  好久不見
Jack. Long time no see.
好久不見
Long time no see.
你還是那麼不修邊幅
I see you're still spendin' all your money on clothes.
是吧
Well, you know.
你如果想要進城看戲
Listen, while you're in town, if you wanna go see a show,
或者蹭個飯什麼的
or want a free meal or something,
就來找我  好嗎
you just let me know, all right?
-我請客  我就是那麼大方  -夠意思
- On me. That's the type of guy I am. - You're a real sport.
-快把磁碟給他  -你媽媽還好嗎
- Just give him the disks. - How's your mother?
-她很好  -你女兒長大了吧
- She's all right. - Your daughter's gettin' big, grown up?
我在想
You know, I was thinkin'.
要是你當時沒有撂挑子
Maybe if we would've done business way back when,
沒準現在也不會混到這個地步
you wouldn't look like a guy with a fuckin' cup in your hand.
不過是討生活罷了
I'm tryin' to make a livin'.
磁碟在你手上嗎
Listen. You got those disks,
還是跟你的工作一起丟了
or so did you lose them like you lost your job?
把磁碟給他  沃爾什
Give him the disks, Walsh.
我是看到你了  但我還沒看到"公爵"
Well, I see you, but I don't see the Duke.
-他的事一會再說  -我現在就要見他
- We'll worry about him in a minute. - We gotta worry about him now.
吉米  我不是來敘舊的
Let me tell you something, Jimmy. This isn't a reunion.
五秒內再見不到"公爵"我立馬走人
If I don't see the Duke in about five seconds, I'm walkin'.
你還是這副兇巴巴的樣兒
You know, you're still way too serious. Really.
不如把碟片給我
Listen. Why don't you just hand over the tapes?
然後一起過去接他
We'll take a walk, get the guy together.
-怎麼樣  -去你媽的  法庭見
- What do you say? - Fuck you, I'll see you at the arraignment.
-傑克  傑克  -他他媽要去哪兒
- Hey, Jack. Jack, hey. - Where the hell is he goin'?
-你贏了還不行嗎  -我什麼
- You win, all right? - I what?
你贏了  我他媽還得拿個擴音器和你說嗎
You won. What you want me to do, yell it all over this fucking airport?
他在哪兒
Where is he?
-這就來  -我說過別帶手下
- He's on his way. - You know, I said no goons.
別管他們  你馬上就要得到你想要的了
Never mind them. You're gonna get what you want.
不是跟你說過了嗎
Didn't I just tell you that?
我都快急出心臟病了
This thing is gonna give me a heart attack before it's all over.
真能急死我
I know I'm gonna get a heart attack.
從我們見面那一刻
Since we have this moment to share together,
我就想問你了
there's something I've been meaning to ask you.
想到自己老婆和別的警察上床是什麼心情
Doesn't it bother you that another cop is fuckin' your wife?
你知道他們提拔他當副巡長了嗎
Do you know they made this guy a captain?
能想像嗎  想想吧  當副巡長的感覺
Can you imagine that? Go figure it out. Made him a captain.
有什麼事  先生
May I help you, sir?
一張去洛杉磯的單程票
Yeah. Give me a one-way ticket to L.A.
去洛杉磯的單程票
One-way ticket to Los Angeles.
要吸煙艙還是禁煙艙
Will that be smoking or nonsmoking?
你說呢
Take a wild guess.
吸煙艙
Smoking.
您準備以什麼方式付款呢  先生
How will you be paying for this, sir?
糟糕
Aw, shit.
-怎麼了  -你看
- What is it? - Look.
他來這幹什麼
What the hell is he doing here?
一名白人男性  一手提綠色旅行包
All right, we have a Male Caucasian carrying a green duffel bag,
一手放在馬甲內  正向目標靠近
hands inside his vest, approaching subjects.
盡快將其制止  避免驚動目標
Get him out of there as quickly and as quietly as possible.
開槍擊斃都行  一定要阻止他
Shoot him if you have to, but get him out of here.
-沒事吧  喬恩  -沒事
- You okay, Jon? - Yeah.
-站我身後  -去吧
- Stand behind me. - It's all right.
好了  給我
All right. Come on.
-別來無恙啊各位  -先在邊上等會行嗎  馬文
- Hey. How's everybody doin'? - Will you get out of here, Marvin?
-所有人退下  -你他媽又是誰
- Back off, everybody. Back off. - Who the fuck are you?
幹什麼  查戶口嗎
What? Are you writin' a book?
-你他媽又是誰  -這人是誰
- Who the fuck are you? - Who is this guy?
-天哪  -馬文  馬文  你闖大禍了
- Jesus. - Marvin. Marvin, you're missin' the bigger picture.
-很嚴肅的告訴你  快走  -你消停
- I'm tellin' ya. Get out of here. - Take a...
通訊斷了
Wire's gone dead.
-你瘋了嗎  -我可不能空手而歸
- Are you crazy? - I didn't come all this way for nothin'.
-塞拉諾在向外走  -他拿到磁碟了嗎
- Serrano's leaving. - Did he take the disks?
-不知道  -塞拉諾拿到磁碟了
- I don't know. - Serrano's got the disks.
-放開他  傑克  -塞拉諾拿到磁碟了
- Let him go, Jack. - Serrano's got the disks.
他有沒有拿到磁碟
Did he or did he not take the disks?
看不清  下面太混亂了
I couldn't tell. There's too much going on down there!
塞拉諾拿到磁碟了  他拿到磁碟了
Serrano's got the disks. He's got the disks.
馬文  馬文  小心  馬文  馬文  小心
Marvin! Marvin, look out! Marvin, Marvin, look out!
你要是以為我還會上當就大錯特錯了
If you think I'm fallin' for that shit again, you're crazy.
馬文  馬文  你這傻逼回頭看看會死啊
Marvin! Marvin, look out! You stupid fucker, will you look out!
塞拉諾拿到磁碟了  塞拉諾拿到磁碟了
Serrano's got the disks! Serrano's got the disks!
行動
Move in.
聯邦調查局
F.B.I!
-輕點兒  拜託  -起來
- Take it easy! Come on! - Get up.
他媽的  你們又他媽是誰
Ow! Goddamn it! Who the fuck are you guys?
吉米  有句話
Jimmy, there's something
我十年前就想對你說了
I've been wanting to say to you for 10 years.
-是嗎  什麼  -你被捕了
- Oh, yeah? What's that? - You're under arrest.
以後我們還會再見面的
Maybe we'll catch up with each other one of these days.
或許吧
Maybe we will.
-咱倆的交易還作數嗎  -當然
- We still got our deal? - We got a deal.
等等  什麼交易
Hey. Hey, wait a minute. What deal?
他怎麼就有特殊待遇
Why the fuck does he get special treatment?
洛杉磯見  馬文
See you in L.A., Marvin.
小心他偷你的煙  傑克
Watch your cigarettes with this guy, Jack.
發生了什麼
What's going on?
抱歉  喬恩  只剩一個半小時帶你回洛杉磯了
Sorry, Jon. I got an hour and a half to get you back to L.A.
謝了  阿朗佐
Thanks, Alonzo.
歡迎來到洛杉磯
莫斯康保釋代理
Yeah? Mascone Bail Bonds.
你好啊  艾迪
Hello? Eddie?
-傑裏呢  -別管他了  你在哪兒呢  傑克
- Where's Jerry? - Never mind Jerry. Where the hell are you, Jack?
聯調局的人二十分鐘前把他抓走了
The feds picked him up 20 minutes ago.
-為什麼  -這不重要  夥計
- Yeah? What for? - What's the difference, man?
我就沒信過這傢伙  你在哪兒
I never trusted that guy anyway. Where the hell are you?
我在哪兒  在機場呢  猜猜誰和我一塊
Where am I? I'm at the airport. And guess who I'm with.
-是"公爵"哦  -你抓到他了
- I'm with the Duke. - You got him!
你抓到他了  傑克  我愛死你了
Oh, you got him, Jack! I love you!
-想打個招呼嗎  -當然  讓他接電話
- Yeah. You wanna say hello? - Yeah. Put him on.
-問個好  -你好
- Say hello. - Hello.
好你個狗雜種  終於抓到你了  王八蛋
Hello, you son of a bitch! We got you, you son of a bitch!
順便道個別吧  你個滿口謊言的王八蛋
Yeah. Now, say good-bye, you lyin' little piece of shit,
我要放他走了
because I'm lettin' him go.
傑克
Jack?
本來能開家不錯的咖啡館
Would've been a nice coffee shop.
天哪
Oh, geez. Oh...
我不明白
I don't get it.
我想做的事已經做完了  喬恩
I did what I wanted to do, Jon.
午夜之前把你帶回洛杉磯  所以
I got you to L.A. before midnight, so...
-我不知道該說什麼了  -那就什麼也別說
- I don't know what to say. - Don't... Don't say anything.
你那德性  說不定又說得我反悔了
Knowing you, you'll make me wanna put those back on you again.
-謝謝  -不  喬恩  是我謝謝你
- Thanks. - No, Jon. Thank you.
謝謝
Thank you.
就當是這段歷險的紀念吧
Something to remember our adventure by.
傑克
Jack?
最好是好事
This better be good.
是好事  好得不得了
This is good. This is very good.
準備逃命的時候
When I was makin' my getaway,
我以為調查局已經盯上我了
I thought the F.B.I. was closin' in on me.
拿著  拿著
Take it. Take it.
就隨身帶了些逃命錢  拿著 拿著
I took some traveling money. Take it. Take it.
這不是賄賂  而是禮物  你已經放我走了
It's not a payoff. It's a gift. You already let me go.
你個王八蛋
You son of a bitch.
-王八蛋  -我告訴過你我有錢
- You son of a bitch. - I told you I had money.
我知道你有錢  但不知道就在你身上
I know you had money. I didn't know you had money.
-這兒有多少  -大概三十萬
- How much is here? - Neighborhood of 300,000.
真是
That's a...
這個"大概"挺厲害
That's a very respectable neighborhood.
不知道說什麼好了  喬恩
I don't know what to say, Jon.
保重
Take care.
-保重  -下輩子見
- Take care. - See you in the next life.
-下輩子見  -下輩子見
- See you in the next life. - See you in the next life.
-請問幾點了  -十一點三十五
- You know what time it is? - Twenty-five to 12:00.
十一點三十五  本來是來得及的
Twenty-five to 12:00. I would've made it.
你找得開一千塊嗎
You wouldn't have change of a thousand, would ya?
你來搞笑的吧
What are ya, a comedian?
一邊玩兒去  流浪漢
Get outta here, ya bum!
看來得走回家了
Looks like I'm walkin'.
「翻譯」日豐味兒牛奶器
「校對」somehacker
「時間軸」大鯀治水  芒果樹葉  chance-coco
「後期」bongpong
「總監」somehacker